<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>ESAI Morales

ACTOR

Age: 39

Height: 5'10"

Status: Never Married

Residence: A ranch-style house in the Hollywood Hills

Education: Attended Manhattan's High School for the Performing Arts

The scoop: Fifteen years ago Esai (pronounced "E-sigh") Morales rocked audiences as Ritchie Valens's troubled older brother in La Bamba. But the music slowed, and the Brooklyn-born son of Puerto Rican parents languished in small roles until last year, when NYPD Blue creator Steven Bochco put out an all points bulletin for a new police lieutenant. "We were worried he wasn't old enough to be a boss in that I squad," says Bochco. "But when he came in to audition, he had such command of the room that any doubts we had were gone." Morales just wrapped up his first full season on Blue and is now hotfooting it between roles on two other TV series: Showtime's Resurrection Blvd. and the PBS drama American Family, about a Hispanic family in L.A. Of his newly hectic schedule, which includes serving as a vice president of the Screen Actors Guild, Morales says, "After so many years of ambiguous work prospects, I welcome it!"

In his own words: "I'm a terminal Libra," he says. "I look for the yin and yang in everything."

The ideal woman: "I used to fall for the girl who needed to be taken care of," says the actor, who lives with his cat Gizma (pictured) and pet rabbit Usagi. But now, "I like a woman who challenges me."

What a catch: "In high school Esai was gorgeous and always chasing girls," recalls former classmate and Resurrection costar Elizabeth Peña. "He's still gorgeous!"

BEN Affleck

ACTOR/SCREENWRITER/PRODUCER

Age: 29

Height: 6'2"

Status: Never married

Residences: Los Angeles and Manhattan

Education: Attended University of Vermont and Occidental College

The scoop: The strapping flyboy of Armageddon and Pearl Harbor was a natural to inherit Harrison Ford's mantle as CIA agent Jack Ryan in The Sum of All Fears. Next, he battles evil—in red leather—playing comic-book hero Daredevil.

In his own words: After alcohol rehab last summer, Affleck, who turns 30 in August, speaks increasingly of marriage and family. "What's going to mean the most to me," he recently told Diane Sawyer, is "being a father, being a husband, being a person of whom I can really be proud."

The ideal woman: His relationship with Gwyneth Paltrow ended in 1999, but she remains the gold standard. Says Bronwen Hughes, who directed Affleck in Forces of Nature: "I think in Gwyneth he found a match of the minds. That seems important to him."

What a catch: Affleck is "amazingly bright, aware and thoughtful," says Daredevil producer Gary Foster. "He doesn't come across like a love-'em-and-leave kind of guy."

ENRIQUE Iglesias

SINGER

Age: 27

Height: 6'1"

Status: Never married

Residence: Miami

Education: Attended University of Miami

The scoop: The Madrid-born son of Latin crooner Julio Iglesias kept his musical dreams secret from <NODE id="2940" />his<NODE id="2943" /> parents (Mom is <NODE id="2960" />Julio<NODE id="2965" />'s ex-wife, <NODE id="2977" />Isabel Preysler<NODE id="2992" />) until he signed with a Mexican label to record 1996's Grammy-winning Enrique Iglesias. Now a crossover sensation who has sold 30 million albums, he says last year's multiplatinum Escape and its hit "Hero" have helped him shed the "Latin lover" categorization that he finds "tacky and embarrassing." Explains Iglesias: "I'm Latin and I always will be. But my music is not."

In his own words: "I'm more nervous about going on a first date" than going onstage. I'm a little shy."

The ideal woman: Despite steamy kissing scenes with tennis ace Anna Kournikova in the "Escape" video, the teen idol insists the two are "just friends." In fact, he claims, he hasn't had a girlfriend in six years. "In my career position it's hard to find someone you can really trust," he says. "I wouldn't want to give my all to someone who is with me simply because of who I am."

What a catch: "Girls sort of moan when he walks by," says Carlos Iglesias (no relation), onetime manager of B.E.D., a South Beach restaurant and club Enrique frequents. "He stops them in their tracks."

ROB Frisbee

THE AMAZING RACE WINNER

Age: 29

Height: 6'1"

Status: Never married

Residence: West Hollywood

Education: Law degree from Harvard

The scoop: After he and roommate Brennan Swain beat out 10 teams to win the CBS reality series' $1 million prize last year, both left the L.A. law firm where they met.

In his own words: "Going back to the office," says Frisbee, who modeled to help fund law school, "just seems like your life's on mute." The aspiring writer now has an agent shopping his sci-fi novels around.

The ideal woman: Someone with "that subtle combination of hard and soft," he says.

What a catch: "<NODE id="4682" />He<NODE id="4684" /> can be too intense," says mom <NODE id="4715" />Linda<NODE id="4720" />. "But he can also have more fun than anyone I've known."

BRENNAN Swain

THE AMAZING RACE WINNER

Age: 30

Height: 6 ft.

Status: Never married

Residence: West Hollywood

Education: Law degree from Regent University

In his own words: "The dating scene can be tough," says Swain, who invested most of his winnings and is pursuing an acting career. "I definitely want to get married."

The ideal woman: "A girl who's into the outdoors and has strong family ties," he says. An interest in his collection of Star Wars paraphernalia wouldn't hurt: "I'm a sci-fi geek."

What a catch: He knows the importance of the "silly little stuff that girls love," says Race competitor and ex-girlfriend Emily Hoyt, 22, to whom he presented a copy of The Goonies, one of her favorite movies.

TOBEY Maguire

ACTOR

Age: 26

Height: 5'8"

Status: Never married

Residence: Los Angeles

Education: Received a high school equivalency diploma

The scoop: Best known as the doe-eyed teen in films like The Ice Storm and Wonder Boys, a newly buff Maguire swooped into theaters in May as the spandex-clad Spider-Man, smashing box office records.

In his own words: "I had never read a comic book before I was cast in this film," says Maguire, who left school in ninth grade to act. "But I'm sure I fantasized about having special powers like flying or being invisible."

The ideal woman: "It's hard to predict what I want in a partner," Maguire told USA Weekend. "It's more about what the universe brings to me." Though it has been alleged the universe recently brought him Spidey costar Kirsten Dunst, he has categorized her as "just a friend."

What a catch: "He's got magnetism," says Spider-Man director Sam Raimi. "He's subtle and quite powerful in his stillness."

JIMMY Sommers

MUSICIAN

Age: 32

Height: 5'11"

Status: Never married

Residence: Los Angeles

Education: Southern Illinois University, B.S.

The scoop: Last year, the Chicago-born saxophonist, who picked up the instrument in fourth grade, released his second jazz CD, 360 Urban Groove. When he's not practicing or performing (some 50 shows a year in the U.S. and abroad), he checks in at Koi, the sushi restaurant he co-owns in L.A.

In his own words: "I definitely have a talent for having a good time," says Sommers, who took one lucky girlfriend on the date of a lifetime: "I told her to take time off, and we flew first-class to Thailand, where we went on my friend's 200-ft. boat and lived like kings for 10 days," recalls Sommers, who delivered a Valentine's Day concert mid-voyage.

The ideal woman: "For some reason I always go toward brown hair and brown eyes," he says. "It's not really shallow—you have to start somewhere."

What a catch: "He's an all-around good guy," says <NODE id="7458" />his<NODE id="7461" /> sister <NODE id="7469" />Janet Friedrichs<NODE id="7485" />. "And when he takes out that saxophone, everybody stops and listens!"

CHRIS Kattan

COMEDIAN

Age: 31

Height: 5'7"

Status: Never married

Residence: New York City

Education: Attended California State University at Northridge

The scoop: A member of the Saturday Night Live crew since 1996, Kattan, who got his start in comedy with the L.A. improv group the Groundlings, is best known for playing SNL's irrepressible exotic dancer Mango.

In his own words: "I'd love to have a child," says Kattan, who stars in the summer film Undercover Brother. "Either one or 40. I love kids." Such plans are on hold for now. "I wouldn't want my wife to have to take care of our children every night because I'm working."

The ideal woman: "I like women who are okay with who they are," he says. They also have to be okay with spending Saturday nights alone, "unless you want to have a date at 4 a.m."

What a catch: "I set him up with this girl who mentioned once that she liked monkeys," says friend Carmen Cuba, a casting director. "So he got an animal trainer to bring one to her house for an afternoon."

MICHAEL Vartan

Age: 33

Height: 6 ft.

Status: Never married

Residence: Los Angeles

Education: Attended high school in Pontoise, France

The scoop: The French-born actor, who first attracted attention as Drew Barrymore's high school teacher in Never Been Kissed, now plays CIA agent Michael Vaughn on ABC's hit, spy series Alias. Vartan left France at 18 to settle in L.A. with <NODE id="8966" />his<NODE id="8969" /> artist mom, <NODE id="8982" />Doris<NODE id="8987" />, arid stepdad, writer <NODE id="9010" />Ian Lafrenais<NODE id="9023" />. "I definitely feel more American," says Vartan. "My standard wardrobe is jeans, a T-shirt and my hockey hat on backwards. I'm a good old Yankee."

In his own words: "I love hockey more than anything," says Vartan, who hits the ice for pickup games two or three times a: week. Apart from sports, "my secret favorite thing on earth is ketchup. I will put ketchup on anything. But it has to be Heinz."

The ideal woman: "The No. 1 quality I look for is being friendly," says Vartan, who ended a 10-year relationship with actress Shannon Gleason three years ago. "She's got to have a sweet demeanor." Adds his Alias costar Jennifer Garner: "I know she'll be grounded and unimpressed with the Hollywood side of his life."

What a catch: "He's smart, funny and handsome," says Garner. "And when he speaks French, forget it!"

DALE Earnhardt Jr.

RACECAR DRIVER

Age: 27

Height: 6 ft.

Status: Never married

Residence: Mooresville, N.C.

Education: Automotive mechanic diploma from Mitchell Community College in Mooresville.

The scoop: In only two years on the NASCAR circuit, the son of racing legend Dale Earnhardt Sr., who was killed in a crash last year, has won $10 million—and a fervid fan base. "At almost every autograph session we get at least one gal that comes up and is either weeping or shaking or unable to speak," says Jade Gurss, friend and coauthor of Driver #8, Earnhardt's memoir of his rookie season.

In his own words: When it comes to racing, he says, "part of me has to have that risk and that danger and that element of not knowing. That sets me aside from most men."

The ideal woman: "She has to be real tough and career-oriented, but I also want her to be with me and want to be at the races. If I see just a hint of a lack of interest, it won't work."

What a catch: Says Earnhardt: "I've done my own laundry since I was 10."

KEN Oringer

CHEF/RESTAURATEUR

Age: 36

Height: 5'8"

Status: Never married

Residence: Boston

Education: Bryant College, B.S.; Culinary Institute of America

The scoop: As a high school baseball pitcher in Paramus, N.J., Oringer says he "didn't go around talking about the consommé and roast chicken I'd made last night." But by college, his passion for cooking won points with dates. "I could cook a meal from whatever a girl had in her refrigerator," he says. Now impressing diners with French-Asian fusion at his Boston eatery Clio's, Oringer won last year's James Beard Award for Best Chef in the Northeast. "Ken lives for food," says <NODE id="11518" />his<NODE id="11521" /> twin brother <NODE id="11535" />Mitch<NODE id="11540" />, a banker.

In his own words: "By the time I was 13 I'd tried every spice in the house."

The ideal woman: "It's nice when someone cooks for me—even a grilled cheese," says Oringer, who hopes to balance work with marriage within five years. "When I do meet the right person, she'll pull me away from the stove."

What a catch: "He's very successful and could be pretentious," says Mitch. "But he drinks beer and eats greasy hamburgers and knows how to have fun."

VICTOR Webster

ACTOR

Age: 29

Height: 6'5"

Status: Never married

Residences: Los Angeles and Toronto

Education: San Clemente (Calif.) High School

The scoop: He was a stockbroker, model, commercial actor and soap star (NBC's Days of Our Lives) before winning the part of superhero Brennan Mulwray on the syndicated sci-fi TV series Mutant X. Now Webster, a black belt in tae kwon do, gets to "fly around, do backflips off walls, shoot people with electricity, do my martial arts, be the sarcastic bad boy am make money," he says.

In his own words: "I talk to everybody—man, woman and child—at the coffee shop, the line at the grocery, everywhere."

The ideal woman: "I want to ride my Harley and have her wrap her arms around me, hold on tight and kiss the back of my neck and mean it."

What a catch: Says <NODE id="12818" />his<NODE id="12821" /> mom, <NODE id="12827" />Roswitha Baughman<NODE id="12844" />: "He was a charmer from the age of 3."

ETHAN Zohn

SURVIVOR: AFRICA WINNER

Age: 28

Height: 5'10"

Status: Never married

Residence: New York City

Education: Vassar College, B.A.

The scoop: Once a globetrotting pro soccer goalie, Zohn now rooms with two buddies in Manhattan, using most of the $1 million he bagged on the CBS reality series to fund AIDS education and soccer programs in Zimbabwe and the U.S.

In his own words: "I didn't want to sell my dignity or self-respect on Survivor," he says. "I wanted to prove you don't have to be backstabbing to win."

The ideal woman: She's an independent, fun-loving, adventurous breadwinner. "I'm definitely going to have to be the stay-at-home dad," Zohn says. "I could never have a 9-to-5 job."

What a catch: He can pull spaghetti through his nose, but his real appeal is that "he totally gets girls," says Annie Venier, a pal from hometown Lexington, Mass. "He knows women better than anyone I Know."

SAM Page

Age: 26

Height: 6 ft.

Status: Never married

Residence: New York City

Education: Princeton University, B.A.

The scoop: With only a few credits to his name (among them a guest spot on The WB's 7th Heaven), Page landed a role in March on ABC's All My Children, playing shady attorney Trey Kenyon.

In his own words: "A great way to live in New York is with a job on a show, to be young and not have to worry about where your next check is going to come from," he says. "I couldn't imagine struggling as an actor here."

The ideal woman: Page says he has no specific criteria, "because if you're looking for something, you're going to miss out on who you might be happier with."

What a catch: Says <NODE id="14513" />his<NODE id="14516" /> sister <NODE id="14524" />Emeline<NODE id="14531" />: "You can tell what a guy is going to be like by how he treats his mom, and he calls her every other day to say hello."

BRUCE Becker

ICE CREAM ENTREPRENEUR

Age: 34

Height: 5'11"

Status: Divorced

Residence: Manhattan

Education: University of Maryland, B.A.

The scoop: The Becker brothers' ice cream hot spot, Max &amp; Mina's in Queens, offers fear-factor flavors like nova lox, beer and nuts, and garlic—based on recipes from grandfather Max Sockloff, a chemist who died in 1985.

In his own words: "When I found my grandpa's recipe book, it was like a treasure map," says Bruce, who named Max &amp; Mina's after his grandparents.

The ideal woman: Someone who "loves me for me—everything else will fall into place."

What a catch: "<NODE id="15265" />He<NODE id="15267" /> has a really good heart," says sister <NODE id="15306" />Elise Cohen<NODE id="15317" />.

MARK Becker

ICE CREAM ENTREPRENEUR

Age: 28

Height: 5'7"

Status: Never married

Residence: Manhattan

Education: Queens College, B.S.

In his own words: "Everyone likes to talk to an ice cream guy," says Mark, who meets women at charity events. "I say, 'Have you tried our corn or peanut flavors?' Ice cream never fails."

The ideal woman: "If she's willing to try garlic ice cream," he says, "I know her horizons are open."

What a catch: "He's very flirtatious but clearheaded," says Beth Smith, a friend from hunger-relief fund Rock and Wrap It Up! "I can't imagine him watching sitcoms. What he and Bruce call leisure time is time to help others."

TY Pennington

CARPENTER

Age: 37

Height: 6 ft.

Status: Never married

Residence: Atlanta

Education: The Art Institute of Atlanta

The scoop: As one of two carpenters in residence for TLC's home renovation program Trading Spaces, Pennington, a former model and set designer who learned the art of woodworking from his father, has helped build a huge fan base for the cable hit, which averages about 11.9 million viewers a week. "I thought it was going to be just another cable home-improvement show, so I'm completely awestruck by its popularity," says Pennington, who also runs his own custom-furniture shop, Furniture Unlimited, in Atlanta. "I love building things with my hands," he adds. "But it's also great to be funny and a complete ham on television. I'm the kid who never grows up. I want to have fun my entire life."

In his own words: "I like to be the center of attention, that's for sure," he says. But when it comes to approaching women? "I'm shy as hell. Everyone will be telling me, 'Do you not see the signs? She is giving you the green light!' But I never make the first move."

The ideal woman: "Independence is attractive," says Pennington, who plays guitar (he has 12), surfs and plays soccer in his free time. "I like people who don't rely on anyone else and who can make do with or without you."

What a catch: On location in Piano, Texas, one day, "we had one stranger approach him in a wedding dress and ask him to marry her," says Trading Spaces host Paige Davis. "He's this fun, good-looking, sexy, fabulous carpenter. How are you going to pass that up, really?"

MATTHEW Von Ertfelda

RESTAURANT CONCEPT DESIGNER

Age: 32

Height: 5'11"

Status: Never married

Residence: Washington, D.C.

Education: Cornell University's School of Hotel Administration

The scoop: Von Ertfelda spent two years in Taiwan modeling and learning Mandarin Chinese before landing a job designing restaurants for hotel giant Marriott International. Among his current projects: a French brasserie in Germany, for which he has recommended everything from the menu to the mosaic flooring. He calls his job, which takes him all over the world, "the coolest in my industry."

In his own words: "I've never made decisions based on money," he says. "It's always been, 'What experience am I going to get out of this?' "

The ideal woman: She has "a nice balance between country and cosmopolitan, with small-town values and big-city style," he says.

What a catch: "Matthew is so worldly," says spa executive Stephanie Loeber, a pal from Cornell. "He is always teasing the other guys. With women, though, he can be so gallant."

STEVE Harris

ACTOR

Age: 36

Height: 6 ft.

Status: Never married

Residence: Los Angeles

Education: Northern Illinois University, B.A.; University of Delaware, M.F.A.

The scoop: Harris, who plays lawyer Eugene Young on ABC's The Practice, grew up in Chicago dreaming of a pro football career. But when a senior-year injury ended those hopes, he turned to acting.

In his own words: "I would never go to a movie on a first date," says Harris, who later this month will appear with Tom Cruise in Minority Report. "You spend two hours with someone you don't know in the dark, silent."

The ideal woman: "I like women who have flavor," says Harris. "I can't really define what that is, but I can smell it when she's got it." What he doesn't like, says Practice costar Kelli Williams, is scrawny women: "He gets on the skinny girls' cases around here and tells them to eat more."

What a catch: Costar <NODE id="19505" />Camryn Manheim<NODE id="19519" />, the single mother of 15-month-old <NODE id="19555" />Milo<NODE id="19559" />, says Harris worries that her son "won't get the things that a father figure brings to a family. He has taken it upon himself to teach Milo how to play sports and has man-to-man chats with him."

MATT Zarley

SINGER/ACTOR

Age: 33

Height: 5'9"

Status: Single and gay

Residence: Los Angeles

Education: Sunny Hills High School, Fullerton, Calif.

The scoop: At the age of 12, Zarley shot a TV commercial with Tony the Tiger. By 19, he had performed in Cats and Broadway's A Chorus Line. He now appears in the Las Vegas Stevie Wonder tribute Signed, Sealed, Delivered as the cast's "lonely white guy," he says.

In his own words: "When I had my first relationship, it was a serious one," says Zarley. "So it's probably been good for me to be single for a while. But I'm ready not to be."

The ideal partner: "I'm looking for somebody I can trust, somebody I can take home to my parents," says Zarley, who in April released his first CD, Debut, a collection of contemporary pop songs.

What a catch: Says longtime pal actress Jolie Jenkins: "He is a warm and sensitive guy, and he knows what hair products to use."

ZACH Braff

ACTOR

Age: 27

Height: 6 ft.

Status: Never married

Residence: A two-bedroom house in L.A.

Education: Northwestern University, B.A. in film

The scoop: The star of NBC's breakout comedy Scrubs caught the acting bug watching his attorney father, Harold, perform community theater in South Orange, N.J. "I knew <NODE id="21000" />I<NODE id="21001" /> had to be part of it," says the third of three sons (mom <NODE id="21059" />Anne<NODE id="21063" /> is a psychologist), whose first audition was for a local production of The Music Man. "I ended up Trombone Player #1. Things have turned around since."

In his own words: "I don't date for the sake of dating," says Braff. "But if I meet someone I like, it's different. If the girl can handle it, I like to do something random. One of my best dates was when we walked into a church and went to an Indian wedding."

The ideal woman: Potential sweeties must contend with another woman: Annie Hall. "It's one of the most romantic and funny movies of all time," says Braff, who slips Woody Allen's 1977 classic into conversation as a test. "If she says, 'No, I've never seen it,' I go, 'You know what? I have to get up early.' "

What a catch: "Off-camera he has us all in stitches, and he's very thoughtful and charismatic," says Scrubs costar Sarah Chalke. "He recites Romeo and Juliet to all the women on the crew."

CARSON Daly

TV HOST

Age: 29

Height: 6'2"

Status: Never married

Residence: New York City

Education: Attended Loyola Marymount University in L.A.

The scoop: Since 1998 the former L.A. disc jockey has hosted Total Request Live, MTV's afternoon video show. In January, NBC gave Daly another gig, his own late-night talk show, Last Call. "If I do have a day off now, nine times out of 10 I'll just sit on my couch and watch TV," he says.

In his own words: "The best dates are early on in a relationship," says Daly, whose engagement to actress Tara Reid ended last summer. "I love the awkward, gawky, beginning part where you're fidgety with the person."

The ideal woman: "If I'm at a party, my attention is fixated on the unassuming girl in the corner," says Daly. Adds his friend Jimmy Kimmel of Comedy Central's The Man Show: "I think when he ultimately winds up with somebody, it's going to be a pretty wholesome, traditional person."

What a catch: "My nickname for Carson is Buddha," says <NODE id="22978" />his<NODE id="22981" /> sister <NODE id="22989" />Quinn<NODE id="22994" />. "There's a peace inside of him that he's had for as long as I can remember."

JAY McGraw

SELF-HELP AUTHOR

Age: 22

Height: 5'11"

Status: Never married

Residence: Dallas

Education: University of Texas at Austin, B.S.

The scoop: When publishers asked Oprah's resident pop psychologist and bestselling self-help author Dr. Phil to write a book for teens, <NODE id="23354" />his<NODE id="23357" /> son <NODE id="23362" />Jay<NODE id="23365" /> said, "Dad, what do you know about high school these days? That world is totally different. Let me write it." Four books later (his first, Life Strategies for Teens, was a bestseller), Jay tours the country promoting his version of the elder McGraw's tough-love life principles.

In his own words: "I'm not shy about giving advice to friends if they ask," says Jay, who just completed his first year of law school. "But I try to be a friend and not a life strategist."

The ideal woman: She "probably wouldn't like that I'm stubborn," he admits. "But I hope she would also say I was never a jerk." What a catch: "I'm proudest when I see how Jay treats other people," says his dad. "He's tenderhearted like his mother, but the boy can't sing or dance. He gets that from me."

NATHANIEL David

BIOCHEMIST

Age: 34

Height: 5'10½"

Status: Never married

Residence: A renovated warehouse in San Diego

Education: Harvard, A.B..; Berkeley, Ph.D.

The scoop: In 1999 David cofounded Syrrx, a $225 million biotechnology company that develops drugs to treat cancer, arthritis and diabetes. In May he was named by M.I.T.'s Technology Review magazine as one of the world's Top 100 innovators under 35.

In his own words: "In terms of biospheric load, I wouldn't want to exceed two kids," he says. "With three, of course, you're contributing to overpopulation."

The ideal woman: "Physical grace is very important," says David, who keeps fit by swimming, running and riding his bike. ("I do my thinking when I'm working out.") He also looks for "someone who is neurotic but funny, someone who is comfortable making fun of herself."

What a catch: "I recommend him highly as a boyfriend," says interior decorator Laura Martin Bovard, who dated David five years ago and remains a pal. "I have more fun shopping with him than with any of my girlfriends. He really has fine taste."

MIKE Kohn

BOBSLEDDER/INFANTRYMAN

Age: 30

Height: 6'1"

Status: Never married

Residence: Herndon, Va.

Education: George Mason University, B.S.

The scoop: Competing for the U.S.A. and the U.S. Army, which helped fund his training, he won Olympic bronze (with Sharp and two teammates) in the 2002 four-man bobsled event.

In his own words: "I don't know if it was stupidity or persistence," says Kohn of the decade he spent preparing. "But I always felt I could win a medal."

The ideal woman: He hopes to have three children with an "attractive, athletic" wife who is "family-oriented and goal-oriented."

What a catch: "<NODE id="25860" />He<NODE id="25862" /> used to be a Tom Cruise lookalike," says mom <NODE id="25908" />Barbara<NODE id="25915" />. "But that was before he bulked up."

DOUG Sharp

BOBSLEDDER/ARTILLERY CREWMAN/CHIROPRACTOR

Age: 32

Height 5'10"

Status: Never married

Residence: Jeffersonville, Ind.

Education: Purdue University, B.S.; Palmer College of Chiropractic, Davenport, Iowa

In his own words: "Kohn would say I'm kinda the crazy one," says Sharp, who is also a licensed pilot. "I try to absorb life and enjoy it to the max."

The ideal woman: "She'll be fun-loving, educated and athletic," he says. "Not afraid to break a nail, but classy at the same time."

What a catch: The charismatic chiropractor "has so much energy," says his friend and high school football teammate Eric Maillette, "he could get you excited about digging a ditch."

JOSHUA Jackson

ACTOR

Age: 24

Height: 6 ft.

Status: Never married

Residence: Los Angeles

Education: Attended Kitsilano Secondary School in Vancouver

The scoop: Before joining The WB's Dawson's Creek in 1998 as the easygoing Pacey Witter, Jackson was best known for his role as a hockey player in the three Mighty Ducks films. He has since made 10 more movies, including the upcoming Cowboys and Idiots.

In his own words: "I don't feel that I need to play characters who are role models for young people," Jackson has said. "If you only show them the good, you leave them to explore the bad on their own."

The ideal woman: Creek's North Carolina set makes it "difficult to maintain a relationship," said Jackson, who has dated costars Katie Holmes and Brittany Daniel. "I've got to find myself a nice southern belle."

What a catch: "Josh started each day shaking hands with every crew member and saying hello," says Cowboys director David Semel. "And he ended each day shaking every crew member's hand and saying thank you."

MATT Kuchar

PROFESSIONAL GOLFER

Age: 24

Height: 6'4"

Status: Never married

Residence: Atlanta

Education: Georgia Tech, B.S.

The scoop: The 1997 U.S. Amateur champion shocked the golf world when he turned down sponsorships worth millions so he could complete college. After graduating, he worked briefly as an investment banking trainee before getting back into the swing of things. Kuchar won his first PGA event this March.

In his own words: "You want to hit that perfect shot over and over and over again," he says. "You always want to get better, no matter how good you are."

The ideal woman: "She has to be attractive, athletic and needs to be able to hang out with the guys," says Kuchar, who often has pals over to play Ping-Pong, pool and basketball. She also has to accept that he's "a neat freak," says <NODE id="28494" />Kuchar<NODE id="28500" />'s sister <NODE id="28510" />Becky<NODE id="28515" />. "If you look in his closet, he has his colored shirts, striped shirts and white shirts grouped."

What a catch: Although he's in no rush to marry, he insists that "when I'm in a relationship, I'm in it just for that person. I'm not one to stray off, and I'm not one to look around."

KEVIN Fitzgerald

VETERINARIAN

Age: 50

Height: 6'4½"

Status: Never married

Residence: Denver

Education: Colorado State University, D.V.M.

The scoop: When he's not taping Animal Planet's Emergency Vets or working at Denver's Alameda East Veterinary Hospital, Fitzgerald is performing stand-up comedy. His dating rule: "If you want a nice girlfriend," he says, "you have to be a nice boyfriend."

BRIAN KEITH Jackson

AUTHOR

Age: 34

Height: 6'1"

Status: Single and gay

Residence: Harlem

Education: University of Louisiana at Monroe, B.A.

The scoop: His third novel, The Queen of Harlem, is just out, but before finding his niche in 1997, Jackson toiled as a stand-up comic, an actor and a playwright. "I had no money," he says. "So fear made me write." He takes his inspiration from everyday things—conversations, signs, scenes—which he records in an ever-present notebook.

In his own words: "When I'm at the ocean, I'm humbled by its vastness," says Jackson, who saves a shell from every beach he visits. "The seashells remind me to be humble."

The ideal partner: "I'm oblivious when someone's flirting with me," he says. "But I look for someone who is open, with no predisposed ideas."

What a catch: "Brian is very confident in his individuality," says cousin Ibukun Saucer, who spent her summers at the Jacksons' Monroe, La., home. "Our grandmother shared a lot of wisdom with him when they used to pick pecans together." Adds Jackson: "I try to be good to people every day."

JONNY Moseley

SKIER

Age: 26

Height: 5'11"

Status: Never married

Residence: A three-bedroom house in Tiburon, Calif.

Education: Three years at the University of California-Davis

The scoop: A gold medal winner in freestyle moguls at '98's Nagano Olympics, the three-time World Cup champ was not discouraged by his fourth-place finish at this winter's Salt Lake City Games. "I put on a show for the crowd," says the gregarious inventor of the controversial "Dinner Roll" jump. "What I do on the hill is live entertainment."

In his own words: "I think I could develop into a good husband," he says. "I'll take care of the big things—fix the plumbing, take care of the pools, unclog the toilet. But I'd prefer not to cook dinner."

The ideal woman: "I look for athletic potential. My last girlfriend was a model and not athletic at all," says Moseley, who is now dating an ex-high school classmate, New York City resident Malia Rich, 26. "It was kind of frustrating. You want the model without the model lifestyle." On the other hand, he concedes, "I have a big enough ego as it is. To have two vain people around would be really tough."

What a catch: Moseley, who hosted Saturday Night Live in March, is "definitely a ham—always the one telling the joke," says longtime pal Amy Ross, a lawyer. "<NODE id="31594" />He<NODE id="31596" />'s a wonderful gift giver," adds mom <NODE id="31633" />Barbara<NODE id="31640" />, "and there's always a wonderful note."

QUIRT Hunt

PROFESSIONAL BULLFIGHTER

Age: 23

Height: 5'11"

Status: Never married

Residence: Merna, Neb.

Education: Anselmo-Merna High School

The scoop: Unlike Spanish bullfighting, the U.S. version involves no capes or killing—just barehanded agility and a taste for danger. A top freestyle contender on the Professional Bullfighters Tour, Hunt grew up in the Sandhills of Nebraska. "Being a cowboy is all I ever wanted to do," he says.

In his own words: After two broken legs, two knee surgeries, cracked ribs, fingers and toes, Hunt concludes, "It's good to have a little fear. You have to have respect for the bull."

The ideal woman: His dating experience is "nearly nonexistent," but he says he'd like to get married when he's "30 or 34." Not surprisingly, Hunt's looking for "someone who likes rodeo and won't be scared every time I step into the arena."

What a catch: "Quirt can fix a fence, rope a cow, repair a windmill," says former world bullfighting champ Miles Hare. "He's a real cowboy in every sense of the word." Merna friend Jenny Hutchison adds, "He calls you ma'am and tips his hat. He's a true gentleman."

DONNIE Yen

ACTOR

Age: 38

Height: 5'8"

Status: Divorced

Residence: Los Angeles

Education: Attended Newton (Mass.) North High School

The scoop: Long a martial-arts star in Hong Kong, Yen hopes his move to the U.S. three years ago will further his career. "In any industry when you're new, you have to pay your dues," he says of the supporting roles he's had in Highlander: Endgame and Blade II. "Eventually I would like to play the lead."

DEREK Fisher

BASKETBALL PLAYER

Age: 27

Height: 6'1"

Status: Never married

Residence: Los Angeles

Education: University of Arkansas at Little Rock, B.A.

The scoop: As a teenager in Arkansas, the future Los Angeles Lakers guard sang in a New Edition cover group. "They were in demand," says <NODE id="33558" />his<NODE id="33561" /> mother, <NODE id="33570" />Annette<NODE id="33577" />, 52. "He was so cute! He had a high-low haircut and wore a tuxedo." Now wearing the Lakers' purple and gold, he has helped his team win three Western Conference championships in six years.

In his own words: "My parents have always stayed on me to work harder," he says. "No matter how many good things happen, I always have to work hard to bring more blessings."

The ideal woman: "I want to find someone who is genuine and has personal and professional goals, someone who is spiritual," says Fisher.

What a catch: "Derek is one of those rare individuals in professional sports," says teammate <NODE id="34174" />Rick Fox<NODE id="34182" />, who with actress wife <NODE id="34206" />Vanessa L. Williams<NODE id="34225" /> is on the hunt for Fisher's Ms. Right. "He has great family values. He has such leadership quality, and it makes for a strong man."

DAVID Zinczenko

VICE PRESIDENT AND EDITOR IN CHIEF, MEN'S HEALTH MAGAZINE

Age: 32

Height: 6'2"

Status: Never married

Residences: Allentown, Pa., and New York City

Education: Moravian College, B.A.

The scoop: After years of traveling to launch Men's Health in 30 countries, "it's time to start taking those vacation days and settle down more," Zinczenko says. "I could learn to like the idea of a big family."

JOHN Miller

20/20 COANCHOR

Age: 44

Height: 6 ft.

Status: Never married

Residences: Manhattan and Shelter Island, N.Y.

Education: One year at Emerson College

The scoop: As an Emmy-winning crime reporter based in New York City, Miller has held his own with police brass and Mafia bigs. But off-duty, the man who once grilled organized-crime boss John Gotti and terrorist Osama bin Laden says, "I am shy. I will not walk across a room and say, 'Do you come here often?' "

In his own words: "It is better to be lucky than talented," he says. "I have been a nice combination of the two." Not so lucky in love, Miller acknowledges his "commitment-phobe" rap, though he's working on it.

The ideal woman: Someone who gets his "perverse sense of humor," he says. Mom <NODE id="35543" />Cindy<NODE id="35548" /> adds, "<NODE id="35556" />He<NODE id="35558" /> is not on the prowl like a lot of other people are."

What a catch: "I used to do dinner and a murder," he says, cheerfully admitting to taking dates to crime scenes. But he's a romantic too, having once commandeered a news helicopter to fly a woman from Connecticut to lunch at Manhattan's Plaza Hotel.

CHRIS Beckman

MTV'S REAL WORLD CHICAGO CAST MEMBER

Age: 25

Height: 6'2"

Status: Single and gay

Residence: New York City

Education: Attended University of Massachusetts, Boston

The scoop: He was bucking for a promotion at a now-defunct financial dot-com in Boston when friends at his gym strong-armed him into auditioning for the latest installment of MTV's Real World. "My feeling was 'If I don't get the show, then I'm ready for the real world,' " says Beckman, a recovering alcoholic who has been sober for more than a year. The winner of this year's Congressman Gerry E. Studds Visibility Award for being a positive role model in the gay community, Beckman is now on the lecture circuit and studying acting. "I have a responsibility to talk about where my life was and where it is today."

In his own words: "I'm never going to live with another human being if I can get away with it," says Beckman, after four months of bunking with six strangers. "Once I get into a relationship, yeah, but another roommate? No way. I like my privacy and I like my space."

The ideal partner: "I like good, wholesome people," says Beckman, also an abstract painter who can whip up a mean chicken stir-fry.

What a catch: "Chris is there for you when you need him," says best friend Sandra Weener. "He knows the right thing to say and when to say it."

TOM Hutsler

MODEL/MICROBREWERY OWNER

Age: 46

Height: 6'1"

Status: Never married

Residence: Kansas City, Mo.

Education: Southwest Missouri State University, B.S.

The scoop: Hutsler studied economics before turning to modeling. He returned to the Midwest in 1993, converting an old power station in Parkville, Mo., into a brewery. "I think the only reason I'm not married is I've procrastinated," he says.

RICHARD Linnehan

ASTRONAUT/VETERINARIAN

Age: 44

Height: 6'2"

Status: Never married

Residence: Houston

Education: University of New Hampshire, B.S.; Ohio State University, D.V.M.

The scoop: At age 34, Linnehan left his job as a marine mammal specialist in San Diego to undergo a year of astronaut candidate training for NASA. In 1996 he flew his first of three space shuttle Columbia missions, conducting life-science experiments.

In his own words: "When I'm sitting in a nursing home," he says, "I'd like to be able to say I had been to Mars."

The ideal woman: He wants someone who's "intelligent, articulate, kind, sensuous, athletic, sleek, with the fine lines of the Botticelli painting of Venus rising from the sea." In San Diego getting a date wasn't a problem, says Linnehan, but "in Texas every woman I meet is under 8 or over 80."

What a catch: "Richard has strong values," says <NODE id="38520" />his<NODE id="38523" /> sister <NODE id="38531" />Colleen Duffy<NODE id="38544" />, an administrator for the city of Las Vegas. "Once he finds that perfect, elusive woman, he would definitely be a one-woman man and settle down."

MICHAEL Rosenbaum

ACTOR

Age: 29

Height: 6 ft.

Status: Never married

Residence: Vancouver

Education: Western Kentucky University, B.A.

The scoop: Playing the teenage Superman's nemesis Lex Luthor on The WB's Smallville has earned Michael Rosenbaum fans aplenty, along with the nickname Sexy Lexy.

In his own words: Having to shave his head to play Luthor, says Rosenbaum, who dressed in drag for this spring's film Sorority Boys, wasn't easy. "I was worried it wouldn't grow back," he says. "Now I worry that it grows back so fast you can see it halfway through the day's shoot! I guess that's healthy, right?"

The ideal woman: "There's something in every woman that's attractive," he says. "Her smile, her smirk, her eyes, her hands or her nervous energy. You know what I don't like? If you snort when you laugh. I can't deal with snorting, not even if you're Gwyneth Paltrow or Nicole Kidman."

What a catch: "He can flirt with any female, from a baby to a grandma," says friend Sunja Knapp, an animation production manager. "But when he falls in love, he falls hard. He'll give you the world."

GEORGE Eads

ACTOR

Age: 35

Height: 6'1"

Status: Never married

Residence: Hollywood

Education: Texas Tech University, B.A.

The scoop: Long before he became Nick Stokes on the hit CBS series CSI: Crime Scene Investigation, the native Texan was George Eads, copy machine salesman. "I thought actors were born in Hollywood," he says. "I didn't know how to go about it." Quitting his job to study acting was step one. Two years after moving to L.A. in 1994, he landed a costarring role on the shortlived Aaron Spelling drama Savannah, followed by a brief stint on ER.

In his own words: "I don't think I could witness the evil that men do," Eads says of his CSI occupation. "I am a little too sensitive, and I would probably be one of those guys who burn out."

The ideal woman: "Someone who knows when it's time to be quiet and to enjoy life without words," says Eads, who lives with his yellow Lab, Maverick.

What a catch: "I don't know if anyone will ever catch George," says CSI costar Jorja Fox, "but I can give you 100 reasons why it's worth trying. He's sexy, he's sweet, he's very smart, he's solid."

CHARLES Cohen

REAL ESTATE MAGNATE

Age: 50

Height: 5'11"

Status: Divorced

Residence: Manhattan

Education: Brooklyn Law School, J.D.

The scoop: At his weekend home outside New York City, Cohen watches movies in his own theater, a 26-seat replica of a Broadway landmark. He hopes to remarry, but he's cautious. "I have a new category," he says. "Strip miner—someone who is beyond a gold digger."

TRAVIS Fimmel

MODEL

Age: 22

Height 6 ft.

Status: Never married

Residence: Los Angeles

Education: Attended RMIT University in Melbourne

The scoop: The latest Calvin Klein jeans and underwear icon grew up in rural Australia, the youngest of three sons of Chris, a cattle farmer, and Jennie, a nurse. After a two-year tour of Asia and Europe, he strode barefoot into an L.A. modeling agency a year and a half ago. Soon steamy billboards of Fimmel in his Calvins were literally stopping traffic (officials removed one from a busy London intersection, citing safety concerns). He's studying acting now, he says, because "I love being an idiot, and acting lets you be an idiot."

In his own words: "It's hard to live up to those photos," he says. "It isn't all really me. Thank God for computer editing and special camera lenses and lighting."

The ideal woman: "There is nothing better than an attractive woman who doesn't act attractive," Fimmel says. He also wants someone who likes to travel and doesn't take herself too seriously, and has devised a test for his dream date: "Maybe I'd throw a piece of food at her in a restaurant to see what she'd do. I'd love it if she threw it back."

What a catch: "You will be charmed by him," says his acting coach Ivana Chubbuck. "He makes you laugh and he is very open and very smart."

DAVID Blaine

MAGICIAN

Age: 29

Height: 6 ft.

Status: Never married

Residence: Manhattan

Education: Passaic (N.J.) High School

The scoop: Although Blaine attracted a celebrity following (including Al Pacino and Robert De Niro, both now pals) with conventional magic tricks, in recent years he has been pulling off daring, Houdini-like feats for national TV audiences. In May he stood for 35 hours on a tiny platform atop an 80-ft. pole in New York City's Bryant Park before plunging feet first into a pile of cardboard boxes. His next stunt, he says, will likely involve being "bound up and thrown into a river and trying not to drown."

In his own words: "Being a cop is more dangerous than what I do," he insists.

The ideal woman: "I like to be mesmerized," says Blaine. "I'm hoping to find that one who captivates me completely."

What a catch: Says his close friend Maverick Records co-owner Guy Oseary: "He's engaging, he's smart, he's fit. He's got all those things that women find attractive." Plus, he adds, "I'm sure he shows his girlfriends a trick or two."

ALEXEI Yagudin

FIGURE SKATER

Age: 22

Height: 5'9"

Status: Never married

Residence: Newington, Conn.

Education: Russia's Academy of Sports &amp; Physical Culture in Minsk

The scoop: Reigning at the World Championships for three straight years, Yagudin lost to archrival Evgeni Plushenko in 2001 but made a comeback this year, winning Olympic gold for Russia and regaining his world title. Currently he's touring the U.S. with John Hancock Champions on Ice.

In his own words: Skating since the age of 4, Yagudin spent much of his St. Petersburg childhood on ice. "Now I feel like the happiest person in life, but back then I'd see my friends fishing, playing soccer and hanging out, while I was always skating."

The ideal woman: "I'd like someone who will take care of me, sit with me and watch TV," he says. "Ha! I'm making her sound like a babysitter!"

What a catch: "Sometimes he acts like a brat, but he's an endearing little brat," says fellow skater Kurt Browning. "He's the bad boy—and the boy next door. He's approachable. A girl can meet him and think, 'Hey, he could like me.' "

WILMER Valderrama

ACTOR

Age: 22

Height: 5'8"

Status: Never married

Residence: Los Angeles

Education: L.A.'s William Howard Taft High School

The scoop: His role as foreign exchange student Fez on FOX's That '70s Show echoes real life. Raised in Venezuela, the Spanish-speaking actor moved with his family to L.A. when he was 14 and didn't learn English until high school.

In his own words: "When you barely speak English, you're excluded from a lot. At 16, I finally started raising my hand in class."

The ideal woman: "I like someone with ambition, someone who respects herself and is proud of who she is," says Valderrama, whose 18-month relationship with singer Mandy Moore ended last winter.

What a catch: "He's one of the funniest guys I've ever met," says '70s costar Laura Prepon. "Our director won't put us in scenes together because he makes me laugh so much."

KEVIN Armstrong

ORTHOPEDIC SURGEON

Age: 36

Height: 6'1"

Status: Never married

Residence: Seal Beach, Calif.

Education: Princeton, B.S.; UCLA, M.D.

The scoop: Armstrong is a knee and shoulder specialist in the orthopedics department at the University of California, Irvine. Currently team doctor for three local high schools as well as for athletes at UCI, the former college football cocaptain says he likes being able to "intertwine athletics with my medical career."

In his own words: "To be with someone and continue to grow with that person for the rest of your life—that's the big prize."

The ideal woman: "I like independent, assertive women," says Armstrong, who plays pickup basketball once or twice a week to stay fit. "Anyone who's meek would not do well around me."

What a catch: "Every woman who knows him, depending on her age, either wants to have his baby or be his mom," says his high school English teacher Laurie Kasparian, who sees Armstrong at reunions and sports events. "Everyone is drawn to him."

JOHN Matz

OPERA SINGER

Age: 24

Height: 6'5"

Status: Never married

Residence: Palm Beach Gardens, Fla.

Education: Attended University of Miami

The scoop: A former high school offensive lineman who sang the national anthem at his football games, Matz made his solo debut at New York City's Metropolitan Opera House on his 23rd birthday. "A lot of people with great voices lack that star quality," says the tenor's voice teacher, Cesar Ulloa, "but I believe John has it." If he weren't singing, the Saturday Night Live fan says, "I think I'd like to be a comedian."

In his own words: "Caffeine will do a number on your vocal cords," says Matz. "The same with dairy products—it produces extra mucus, and you don't want that."

The ideal woman: "I'd like to find somebody who can support my career," says Matz, who concedes that his unpredictable schedule makes dating a challenge. "Then, when I'm traveling, I'll have that lighthouse at home to come back to."

What a catch: Not only can he "dust things that are really high," he says, but he's also kind to animals. When he's not touring, he volunteers at a local shelter, cleaning cages and feeding strays.

GEORGE Clooney

ACTOR/PRODUCER/DIRECTOR

Age: 41

Height: 5'11"

Status: Divorced

Residence: Hollywood

Education: Attended Northern Kentucky University

The scoop: The star of Ocean's Eleven donned a director's cap for December's Confessions of a Dangerous Mind, based on the life of TV's Gong Show host Chuck Barris. The jury is still out on the quirky project's chances for success, but one thing is certain—Clooney rules as a Hollywood good guy. "The crew basically gave him a round of applause every day after work," says ex-gal pal Maria Bertrand, a Montreal bartender-actress whom Clooney cast in Confessions. "They loved him. Everyone in town thought he was great."

In his own words: "I really do believe that there's a period of time when you can actually make your mark," Clooney recently told Britain's Observer, explaining his workaholic nature. "This is my shot."

The ideal woman: After <NODE id="48792" />his<NODE id="48795" /> three-year marriage to actress <NODE id="48827" />Talia Balsam<NODE id="48839" /> ended in <NODE id="48849" />1992<NODE id="48853" />, Clooney famously declared he'd never marry again—and courted a string of beauties, including French model Céline Balitran, MTV Europe host Lisa Snowdon and actress Renée Zellweger. But his pal actress Bai Ling sees him settling down with "an extremely good, loving person with a generous nature—just not for a while."

What a catch: "I've never seen anyone lift spirits like him," says Joe Russo, codirector of the upcoming Welcome to Collinwood, which Clooney produced. "He's always funny and he's always looking out for you." Adds former ER costar Ming-Na: "He's got the looks, charm and sense of humor."</TEXT>
<Meta /><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="2940" endPos="2943" type="person" surface="his">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="99_6" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H." /></Entity>
<Entity id="1" startPos="2960" endPos="2965" type="person" surface="Julio">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="119_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="2" startPos="2977" endPos="2992" type="person" surface="Isabel Preysler">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="136_3" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="3" startPos="4682" endPos="4684" type="person" surface="He">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="15_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="4" startPos="4715" endPos="4720" type="person" surface="Linda">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="48_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="5" startPos="7458" endPos="7461" type="person" surface="his">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="50_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="6" startPos="7469" endPos="7485" type="person" surface="Janet Friedrichs">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="61_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="7" startPos="8966" endPos="8969" type="person" surface="his">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="48_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="8" startPos="8982" endPos="8987" type="person" surface="Doris">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="64_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="9" startPos="9010" endPos="9023" type="person" surface="Ian Lafrenais">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="92_4" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="10" startPos="11518" endPos="11521" type="person" surface="his">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="27_3" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="11" startPos="11535" endPos="11540" type="person" surface="Mitch">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="44_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="12" startPos="12818" endPos="12821" type="person" surface="his">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="19_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="13" startPos="12827" endPos="12844" type="person" surface="Roswitha Baughman">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="28_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="14" startPos="14513" endPos="14516" type="person" surface="his">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="19_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="15" startPos="14524" endPos="14531" type="person" surface="Emeline">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="30_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="16" startPos="15265" endPos="15267" type="person" surface="He">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="15_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="17" startPos="15306" endPos="15317" type="person" surface="Elise Cohen">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="56_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="18" startPos="19505" endPos="19519" type="person" surface="Camryn Manheim">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="21_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="19" startPos="19555" endPos="19559" type="person" surface="Milo">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="71_3" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="20" startPos="21000" endPos="21001" type="person" surface="I">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="168_3" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="21" startPos="21059" endPos="21063" type="person" surface="Anne">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="227_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="22" startPos="22978" endPos="22981" type="person" surface="his">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="55_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="23" startPos="22989" endPos="22994" type="person" surface="Quinn">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="66_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="24" startPos="23354" endPos="23357" type="person" surface="his">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="136_3" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="25" startPos="23362" endPos="23365" type="person" surface="Jay">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="144_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="26" startPos="25860" endPos="25862" type="person" surface="He">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="15_3" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="27" startPos="25908" endPos="25915" type="person" surface="Barbara">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="63_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="28" startPos="28494" endPos="28500" type="person" surface="Kuchar">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="54_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="29" startPos="28510" endPos="28515" type="person" surface="Becky">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="70_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="30" startPos="31594" endPos="31596" type="person" surface="He">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="1_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="31" startPos="31633" endPos="31640" type="person" surface="Barbara">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="40_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="32" startPos="33558" endPos="33561" type="person" surface="his">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="28_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="33" startPos="33570" endPos="33577" type="person" surface="Annette">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="40_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="34" startPos="34174" endPos="34182" type="person" surface="Rick Fox">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="93_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="35" startPos="34206" endPos="34225" type="person" surface="Vanessa L. Williams">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="125_3" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="36" startPos="35543" endPos="35548" type="person" surface="Cindy">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="4_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="37" startPos="35556" endPos="35558" type="person" surface="He">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="17_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H." /></Entity>
<Entity id="38" startPos="38520" endPos="38523" type="person" surface="his">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="48_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="39" startPos="38531" endPos="38544" type="person" surface="Colleen Duffy">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="59_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="40" startPos="48792" endPos="48795" type="person" surface="his">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="23_5" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="41" startPos="48827" endPos="48839" type="person" surface="Talia Balsam">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="58_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="42" startPos="48849" endPos="48853" type="date" surface="1992">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="80_3" />
<feature featureName="date_year" featureValue="1992" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="43" NAME="marriage">
<Entity id="2" label="person" />
<Entity id="1" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc1_2841_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="44" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="0" label="person" />
<Entity id="2" label="parent" />
<Entity id="1" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc1_2841_0_749" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="45" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="3" label="person" />
<Entity id="4" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc1_4667_0_750" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="46" NAME="sibling_relationship">
<Entity id="5" label="person" />
<Entity id="6" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc1_7408_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="47" NAME="marriage">
<Entity id="9" label="person" />
<Entity id="8" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc1_8918_0_746" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="48" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="7" label="person" />
<Entity id="8" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="V.M., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc1_8918_2_739" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="49" NAME="sibling_relationship">
<Entity id="11" label="person" />
<Entity id="10" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc1_11491_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="50" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="12" label="person" />
<Entity id="13" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc1_12799_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="51" NAME="sibling_relationship">
<Entity id="14" label="person" />
<Entity id="15" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc1_14494_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="52" NAME="sibling_relationship">
<Entity id="17" label="person" />
<Entity id="16" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc1_15250_0_763" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="53" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="19" label="person" />
<Entity id="18" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc1_19484_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="54" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="20" label="person" />
<Entity id="21" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc1_20832_0_754" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="55" NAME="sibling_relationship">
<Entity id="22" label="person" />
<Entity id="23" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc1_22923_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="56" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="25" label="person" />
<Entity id="24" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc1_23218_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="57" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="26" label="person" />
<Entity id="27" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc1_25845_0_756" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="58" NAME="sibling_relationship">
<Entity id="28" label="person" />
<Entity id="29" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc1_28440_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="59" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="30" label="person" />
<Entity id="31" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc1_31593_0_757" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="60" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="32" label="person" />
<Entity id="33" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc1_33530_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="61" NAME="marriage">
<Entity id="34" label="person" />
<Entity id="35" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc1_34081_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="62" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="37" label="person" />
<Entity id="36" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc1_35539_0_759" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="63" NAME="sibling_relationship">
<Entity id="39" label="person" />
<Entity id="38" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc1_38472_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="64" NAME="marriage">
<Entity id="42" label="to" />
<Entity id="41" label="person" />
<Entity id="40" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc1_48769_1" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
