<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>For Mariel Hemingway it's about balance—and not just the kind that lets her execute the Dancer yoga pose (right) without falling on her face. For Brooke Shields Echinacea tea is the ticket, while Benjamin Bratt lives down his teenage nickname Scarecrow by staying bulked up with rock climbing. They're just a few of the stars who have found a healthy formula for fitness. Sure, it takes dedication (Tobey didn't became Spidey overnight), along with chefs and trainers most can't afford. But we can all relate to the payoff. "It's lovely," says ex-Spice Girl Geri Halliwell, "to feel good about yourself."

Mariel Hemingway Yoga gave her a kinder, gentler way to keep fit

Playing a track star in 1982's Personal Best allowed Mariel Hemingway to showcase her body in its top form. "I ran, I hiked mountains," she says. "I was considered in good shape." But, ironically, her rigorous exercise regimen ("I came from the Jane Fonda make-it-burn mentality," she says) and a fat-free, low-protein diet—mostly fruits, vegetables and popcorn—made the actress unhealthy. "I was getting anemic, and it was causing thyroid and skin problems for me," she says.

Then Hemingway rediscovered yoga. She had practiced it on and off as a teen, but in 1986, after taking a class in power yoga—an aerobicized Western approach to the ancient series of poses that includes strength training—she became a devotee. Today Hemingway, 40, has a dedicated yoga space in the seven-bedroom L.A. house <NODE id="1472" />she<NODE id="1475" /> shares with documentary filmmaker husband <NODE id="1518" />Stephen Crisman<NODE id="1533" />. After rising at 5:30 a.m., <NODE id="1562" />she<NODE id="1565" /> practices for an hour or two, four to six times a week, sometimes with daughters <NODE id="1647" />Dree<NODE id="1651" />, 14, and <NODE id="1661" />Langley<NODE id="1668" />, 12. (Hemingway also owns a yoga studio, Sacred Cow, in Sun Valley, Idaho, her summer home, that offers a variety of classes.) The routine, less stressful than her regimen of 20 years ago, agrees with her. "At the end of a session you feel so fantastic, with a tremendous feeling of peace and well-being," says Hemingway. That spirit goes a long way toward keeping her spry. Thanks to yoga, says Mark Stephens, founder of L.A. Yoga Center, who has taught Hemingway in class, "Mariel has the body of someone 15 years younger."

Hemingway has tweaked her diet as well. Now she eats fish, whole eggs (instead of just egg whites) and a bit of butter along with organic fruits and vegetables. "I eat more like a regular person," she says, adding that today she is much healthier, and her skin "is full of moisture and it doesn't look blotchy anymore."

That's her personal best. Yoga "is about your body," says Hemingway. "I love that it's not a competition, not a sport and not about being better than anyone else."

Catherine Bell Toughening up through Tae-Bo

Before she got her big break playing headstrong Marine attorney Lt. Col. Sarah "Mac" MacKenzie on CBS's JAG, Catherine Bell aspired, she says, to kick big-screen butt in action movies. And so about 10 years ago she wandered into a Tae-Bo studio. "In the first class I had to take a lot of breaks," she recalls, "because I would start to hyperventilate." Still, the high-energy combination of aerobics, boxing and tae kwon do had Bell hooked. "I liked that it was challenging," she says. "It made me want to be in better shape."

Mission accomplished. Bell, 33, "has become an athlete," says Billy Blanks, her trainer and Tae-Bo's creator. "She can do amazing kicks and punches, and she does weights very easily too." Equally impressive are Bell's eating habits. "I try to eat well 80 to 90 percent of the time," she says. Breakfast is often an egg-white omelet, while lean proteins and whole grains such as oatmeal and brown rice are staples. For Bell, a former runway model in Japan, a cheeseless pepperoni-and-sausage pizza counts as a splurge. (She's allergic to dairy.) "And I usually have half a cookie or a couple of bite-size Snickers every day," she says. "I leave room for fun."

Bell, who shares a contemporary home in Malibu Hills, Calif., with <NODE id="3983" />her<NODE id="3986" /> husband, actor <NODE id="4002" />Adam Beason<NODE id="4013" />, 32, pushes herself even harder when JAG is on hiatus, adding mountain biking and hiking to her routine. "I have to do it," she says, "for health and energy."

Vivica A. Fox Getting her kicks from tae kwon do

For <NODE id="4228" />her<NODE id="4231" /> <NODE id="4232" />1998<NODE id="4236" /> wedding to R&amp;B singer <NODE id="4259" />Christopher Harvest<NODE id="4278" />, Vivica A. Fox pulled out all the stops, ordering 1,000 roses and inviting 260 guests. A year later, however, Fox had to rein herself in—after packing on 15 lbs. "It was just from being happy; I was getting too comfortable," she says. "Then I looked in the mirror and went, 'Oh my goodness!'"

These days, though, Fox's reflected image is back to being buff, thanks to the martial arts moves she is mastering for Kill Bill, the upcoming revenge thriller in which she plays a member of a group of elite female assassins. "You can see the effects in her skin, her eyes," says Fox's friend, music industry manager Cassandra Mills. "She looks really healthy." Every day from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. Fox trains in tae kwon do—a high-kicking martial arts technique. "The first week I felt 80 years old," she says. "I'm finding muscles I never knew I had."

Fox, 37, who shares a 6,500-sq.-ft. San Fernando Valley house with Harvest, 32, also practices food discipline. A former devotee of pasta and potatoes, she now sticks to a low-carb diet that includes turkey bacon and eggs for breakfast, grilled chicken and vegetables for lunch and salad or sushi for dinner. "This summer," she says proudly, "will be the first time that I'm absolutely in swimsuit condition!"

Mariska Hargitay No gym—but a lot of swim

In hard-bodied Hollywood, it's a confession as shocking as any Mariska Hargitay hears as Det. Olivia Benson on NBC's Law &amp; Order: SVU. "I don't enjoy exercise," the actress says, "and I don't like going to the gym." Instead she stays in shape with activities "where I feel like I'm doing sports," which explains why she drifted toward swimming. "It reminds me of being in the womb," she says. "You hear your breathing, and it's completely relaxing."

The only daughter of late screen siren <NODE id="6067" />Jayne Mansfield<NODE id="6082" /> and former Mr. Universe <NODE id="6107" />Mickey Hargitay<NODE id="6122" />, 76, <NODE id="6128" />Hargitay<NODE id="6136" />, 38, learned to swim at 6 months and later competed on the varsity swim team at Los Angeles's Marymount High School. Today Hargitay switches between the backstroke, breaststroke, freestyle and butterfly and scouts out new places to take the plunge. During SVU's hiatus last summer, for example, she spent three weeks swimming with wild dolphins off Hawaii's Kona Coast. "For her it's not about 'I've got to look a certain way,'" says her close friend, actress Kelly Miller. "She's motivated by an awareness to take care of herself from the inside."

That includes eating every two hours, with an emphasis on fish and raw fruits and vegetables. As for indulgences, Hargitay, who is single and lives in a 2,500-sq.-ft. Manhattan apartment, says that every morning, "even if it's 5 a.m.," she takes a hot bath to get her blood flowing. "I come to work with these rosy cheeks," Hargitay says. "My makeup artist is like, 'Were you just running?'"

Mathew St. Patrick A body in constant motion

As a teenager in Philadelphia, where he was on the varsity track team at Olney High School, Mathew St. Patrick could, he says, "consume half a pizza and still keep my body fat really low." Today St. Patrick—who plays hunky gay police officer Keith Charles on HBO's Six Feet Under—still relies on running to keep trim, hitting the treadmill or the dirt paths near his Hollywood Hills bungalow at least three times a week for 45 minutes. His pizza-eating days, however, are over. "I just remember what I feel like after eating unhealthy foods," St. Patrick says, "and it's enough to help me stay away."

"What St. Patrick, 34, turns to instead are fresh fruit and vegetable juices (like grape or carrot) that he whips up at home. Breakfast is oatmeal with raisins and egg whites, while dinner is grilled salmon with vegetables or Caesar salad with shrimp. When he does allow himself a treat—favorites include Häagen-Dazs Vanilla Swiss Almond ice cream or apple pie à la mode at Los Angeles' Al Gelato restaurant—he refuses to consider it cheating. "Don't feel bad after eating something," he says. "If you're going to get the guilties, then don't eat it!"

On the weekends St. Patrick, a former personal trainer who describes himself as "single and happy," plays tennis at L.A.'s Griffith Park or hikes the area's surrounding hills. "I have called him many times," says St. Patrick's friend as well as his talent agent Stewart Strunk, "when he's in the middle of a 20-mile bike ride along the Los Angeles coast." Whatever the activity, St. Patrick always makes sure to stretch for a good 30 minutes beforehand. "You can't expect your muscles to perform," he says, "if they're not warmed up."

Weight lifting and sets of 100 push-ups and sit-ups round out his routine—which means that St. Patrick never has to worry if the Six Feet Under script calls for a shirtless love scene. "I just pop a breath mint," he says, "and keep going!"

Hot Spots Those arms, those abs, that absence of flab! These stars are toned all over, but here's a close look at their finest features

They say the camera adds 10 lbs.—so staying trim and toned in Hollywood must be almost as tough as winning an Oscar. "All these actresses that look amazing—I don't think people have any idea how hard it is to maintain," says Valerie Waters, Alias star Jennifer Garner's personal trainer. "It's a lot of work to keep your body that way." So, in recognition of that endless labor, we've chosen those physical attributes we think have benefited from it most. From Ben's chest to Geri's abs, each qualifies as a perfect part—and as any actor can tell you, finding those in Hollywood is rare indeed.

Best arms

TOM CRUISETo maintain the bulging biceps he so prominently displays in the Mission: Impossible films, Cruise employs a personal trainer and brings his own mobile gym along on location shoots. "I work hard," he once told PEOPLE, "but I love to work hard." With results like these, who wouldn't?

JENNIFER GARNERBefore landing the lead on Alias, Garner "looked good," says her trainer, Valerie Waters, "but we had to step it up because spies are in really good shape." Garner keeps her arms toned with "three sets of biceps curls and maybe six sets of triceps" at least thrice weekly, Waters says, adding, "We focus on strength. She's not this girl that's ripped but can't do a pull-up."

Best abs

GERI HALLIWELL "I've been every shape and size," says the former Ginger Spice, who has now figured out what she really, really wants: a balanced mix of cardio, kickboxing and, most importantly, an ab-soluteiy fabulous regimen of sit-ups and three yoga sessions a week. "Yoga's good for strengthening," says Halliwell. "With the breathing, it massages the stomach without your even realizing it."

USHER Talk about suffering for beauty. R&amp;B star Usher squeezes in up to 1,000 stomach crunches every day, and when he's not on tour, he makes four two-hour trips to the gym each week. Still, even he has limits. "I don't touch weights," he says. "It's better to lift your own weight. That's why you see boxers punching the bag, doing jump-rope. It makes you stronger."

Best chest

HALLE BERRY"Even though I like to stay in shape," Berry has said, "I want to stay feminine." With personal trainer Robert White—"the only man I will trust with my body"—Berry does Pilates and a full-body workout with plenty of chest-press exercises, which, she said, "muscles up the right places."

BENJAMIN BRATT The onetime 6-ft., 145-lb. Bratt bulked up in high school by running five miles a day, then hitting the mat for hours of wrestling practice. Now he maintains those muscles with rock climbing, tennis and surfing. As Bratt once told PEOPLE, "I like pushing the limits."

Best legs

PATRICK RAFTER He cross-trains and practices three hours a day before a match. But Rafter can't take all the credit for his killer calves. "It's genetic," says brother Peter. "Dad had great legs too."

NICOLE KIDMAN"Growing up, I'd be described as a colt," says the 5'10" star. "Having long legs makes you geeky." But since she's stuck with them (poor thing), she keeps those gams gorgeous by hiking and swimming. Says Kidman: "I'm kind of a water baby."

Exercising Control Beating an eating disorder marked by excessive workouts teaches a Sopranos star to define beauty her own way

In August 1997, after beating out hundreds of other actresses for the role of Mafia princess Meadow Soprano, Jamie-Lynn Sigler filmed the pilot episode for a new HBO series, The Sopranos. But waiting to hear if the show would be picked up for a full season while juggling school-work and breaking up with her first boyfriend left the high school junior, then 16, feeling "like everything was out of control," she says. By November Sigler had fallen victim to a combination of borderline anorexia and compulsive exercise, restricting her daily calorie intake to less than 500. At the same time, she worked out for as much as four hours a day. "I said, 'This is one thing I can control,'" she recalls. "That was my outlet."

During the next five months the 5'6" Sigler went from 120 to 90 lbs. Although <NODE id="13257" />her<NODE id="13260" /> parents—<NODE id="13269" />Steve<NODE id="13274" />, now 53, an entrepreneur, and <NODE id="13305" />Connie<NODE id="13311" />, 53, a homemaker—expressed concern, "Jamie-Lynn was very good at disguising that this was a problem," says Connie. "She was losing a lot of weight, but I thought it was from running around too much."

In April 1998, Sigler finally realized she had a problem and told her parents, who quickly got her medical help. Now up to a healthy 125 lbs., Sigler, 21, is filming her fourth season on The Sopranos and moving into a one-bedroom Manhattan apartment. She also has a new boyfriend—her manager A.J. Discala—and is awaiting the publication of her autobiography, Wise Girl, in August. But her greatest satisfaction comes from serving as a spokeswoman for the National Eating Disorders Association. "To know that you can change even one person's life," she says, "is amazing." Sigler recounted her struggle to PEOPLE correspondent KC Baker.

It's hard to pinpoint when I went from exercising 20 minutes in the morning to exercising for four hours a day and not really eating. I would have two egg whites for breakfast, and lunch was a scooped-out bagel and a Diet Coke. Dinner turned into a fat-free yogurt. And I couldn't stop exercising. I would wake up at 4 a.m., run for 45 minutes on the treadmill and then do a workout video. When I did laundry, I'd bring one sock at a time to the laundry room so I'd have to take the stairs 10 times. I did squats as I was making my bed.

My grades started dropping because I kept nodding out in class. I was getting colds all the time. My hair was falling out. At school I heard comments like, "Oh my God" and "That's disgusting!" when I walked by.

I wasn't looking in the mirror thinking, "I'm fat." I was looking in the mirror thinking, "I look horrible, but I can't stop this." I was so depressed that at one point the words "I don't want to live anymore" went through my head. That same day I told my parents I needed help.

The next day I was in a psychiatrist's office. It was nice to have someone disconnected from my life who I could tell everything to. A few weeks later I started working with a nutritionist who had me make gradual changes. I would do the treadmill one day and a workout video the next, instead of on the same day. I added a piece of toast to my breakfast and toppings to my yogurt. But I had setbacks. Once, at a party, I had a piece of cake. The next morning I woke up crying, convinced I wouldn't fit into my pants. I ran straight to the gym and worked out for two hours. After that, I got a prescription for Prozac. I started slowly getting better. [She is now off Prozac.]

I went to shoot the first season of The Sopranos in June '98. The cast hadn't seen me in a year. I had been a size 4 or 6 and now I had the body of a 12-year-old. During the wardrobe fitting, I was praying, "Let something fit." [Series creator] David Chase did a double take when he saw me—he didn't know who I was. He went to my mom and said, "What's going on? We love her, but Jamie's got a lot to do in this show, and she has to be physically able to handle it."

I was terrified. I was like, "This is my dream. I can't lose it." I stopped exercising every day and started eating more. By the end of the season I was at a great point. Now I have this normal lifestyle. I work out two or three times a week. I eat when I'm hungry, and I stop when I'm full. In the industry I'm in, I have to be in shape, but I'm not going to torture myself to fit any kind of mold.

I'm not going to lie and say I don't think about what I eat. I don't think an eating disorder is something you ever fully recover from. I get letters from girls who tell me that because I'm talking about it, it makes them feel better. The first time that happened, I said, "This is the true meaning of life."

Pot Luck Their careers are cooking, but what star has the time? Matt, Celine and Pierce's solution: personal chefs who whip up lean cuisine as tasty as Mom's

Matt DamonA star's diet is Bourne

Matt Damon was confronting some weighty issues when he met Alex Hilebronner in 2000. Just cast as an amnesiac assassin in the action thriller The Bourne Identity, due out on June 14, he needed a chef to help him slim down for the part.

The request was a familiar one for Hilebronner, who was working on the set of Damon's film All the Pretty Horses. "I seem to have a reputation for helping people lose weight," says Hilebronner, 38, who previously helped other high-profile celebs—she won't name names—lose weight for big projects. That summer Hilebronner began preparing three meals a day at Damon's L.A. home to complement his extensive workout regimen. "I sat down with him first to find out what he likes and doesn't like," she says. "I know he doesn't love olives, and cream and butter were off-limits, but he's very easy to cook for. He wanted me to be creative and surprise him."

She did just that, with what she calls "boy-friendly" dishes like low-fat pizza and a meal that quickly became one of his favorites, saffron risotto. "When he tasted it, he was like, 'Oh my God, I can't believe I can eat this!'" says Hilebronner. "He loved it." Marvels Damon: "Alex has a way of making food that is healthy and good for you taste good too."

Her job got a lot tougher when she accompanied Damon that fall to film Bourne in Prague. During her first food-shopping trip in the city, where fresh produce is limited, "I started to cry because I thought, 'What am I going to do?'" she says. "You pick up a carrot and it falls over because it's so limp." Her hotel-room cooking facilities were even worse. "It tested everything in me," she says. "I had a little tiny oven that looked like an Easy-Bake Oven and a little minibar refrigerator."

Still, the Santa Barbara, Calif., native isn't complaining. After spending her teenage years cooking dinners each Saturday night for her friends and family, Hilebronner was fired from two jobs in the '90s—checking coats in a fancy Manhattan restaurant and working as a cocktail waitress at the Four Seasons in L.A.—"for being in the kitchen too much, just watching." She finally embraced her inner chef in 1993, taking classes and working for a catering company, before segueing into personal-chef work.

So far Hilebronner has managed to avoid ego clashes with her celebrity clients. "I'm much harder on myself than they are," she says. "I'm wanting it to be five-star every time." She admits that working for Damon provides a unique challenge: trying to keep his constant flow of houseguests from gobbling up Damon's dishes. "A lot of times I'll leave something for him, and somebody else in the house will have eaten it," she says. "Now I plate his food and put a sticker on it saying, 'This is Matt's dinner.'"

Saffron Risotto w/ Steamed Asparagus

4 cups chicken or vegetable stock 1 bunch asparagus, trimmed 1 tbsp. olive oil 1 medium onion, finely diced 1 cup arborio rice ½ cup white wine 1 large pinch of good quality saffron 1/8 cup Italian parsley, chopped fine for garnish shaved Parmesan (optional) for garnish

In a saucepan, heat stock to a slow boil. In another saucepan, blanch asparagus, set aside and keep warm. In a large sauté pan, heat oil, add the onion and cook until translucent. Add arborio, wine and saffron and stir until wine is absorbed. Add hot stock, one ladle at a time, stirring constantly until risotto is tender and creamy and all the liquid is absorbed. Arrange risotto evenly on a plate. Top with steamed asparagus in a pinwheel fashion and sprinkle with chopped parsley and shaved Parmesan. Serves 2

Celine Dion Receiving her just desserts

Titanic fans know that Celine Dion's heart will go on. Chef Bernard Marcel Goupy works to keep her stomach shipshape as well. "I know their limit," he says of Dion and her family. "They like simplicity."

Paris-born Goupy, who picked up his first spatula at age 6, feared that his reputation was julienned when Donald Trump fired him as head chef of his Mar-a-Lago Club in Palm Beach, Fla., in February 2001, telling reporters that Goupy was a "terrible chef." (Goupy, 63, sued Trump for age discrimination; the case was settled for an undisclosed amount.) <NODE id="21412" />Dion<NODE id="21416" /> and husband <NODE id="21429" />René Angélil<NODE id="21441" />, who frequent Mar-a-Lago, disagreed with The Donald's culinary critique and hired Goupy that April. "Bernard has taken such great care to prepare the most healthy and best-tasting cuisine, especially during my pregnancy," says Dion, who occasionally dons an apron and joins him in the kitchen. "Our guests have always been impressed with his creativity."

And his commitment: Goupy spends 16 hours a day, seven days a week at the family's Jupiter, Fla., home (he lives an hour away in Delray Beach), preparing their favorite dishes, including his baked Galia melon dessert, which a delighted Dion declared "very, very special" when he first served it to her last summer. The schedule may seem brutal but not to Goupy. "They take care of me," he says. "I'm part of the family."

Baked Galia Melon, Exotic Fruits and Sherbet

2 Galia melons, cut in half 2 cups seasonal exotic fruits, diced small 1 packet Sweet 'n Low 1 tsp. pure vanilla 6 tsp. plain yogurt 6 egg whites 6 oz. sugar 1 pint sherbet

Remove the pulp from each melon half, leaving the skin intact to form a basket. Dice the pulp and mix with the exotic fruits. Add yogurt, Sweet 'n Low and vanilla and mix gently. Set aside.

For the meringue, put the eggs and a pinch of salt into a mixing bowl. Beat gently until fluffy, then slowly add the sugar. Continue to beat on medium speed till stiff.

Take each melon shell and fill with a scoop each of sherbet and fruit mixture. Top with 1 in. of meringue. Place under broiler for a minute or until the meringue is golden. Serve immediately. Serves 4

Pierce Brosnan Bites of spring (rolls)

James Bond has little difficulty finding a good martini, but where can he turn when he's in the mood for something stir-fried, not shaken? Current 007 <NODE id="23194" />Pierce Brosnan<NODE id="23208" /> and wife <NODE id="23218" />Keely Shaye Smith<NODE id="23235" /> chose carefully before selecting Neil Zevnik as their chef in 2000. "They wanted someone flexible and casual," says Zevnik, "someone accustomed to working around celebrities."

They got their wish. Zevnik's approach, says Keely, "combines healthy eating with good taste and artistic flair." Self-taught, Zevnik, 50, grew up in West Nyack, N.Y. In 1991 he moved to Los Angeles to manage a few high-end restaurants. After filling in for a friend, a personal chef, Zevnik landed a gig with Elizabeth Taylor, a job that lasted seven years.

As the Brosnans' chef, Zevnik prepares at least one meal a day—and caters dinner parties and birthday festivities for kids <NODE id="23896" />Dylan<NODE id="23901" />, 5, and 15-month-old <NODE id="23923" />Paris<NODE id="23928" />—in the family's Malibu home. "They're really healthy," says Zevnik of the Brosnan clan. Environmental journalist Keely, 38, whose edible-gardening book Gourmet Gardener (complete with a few Zevnik-tested recipes) is due out next year, consults on his dish choices. As for Brosnan, 50, "he just wants to be involved in the eating!" says Zevnik.

Especially when the menu includes spring rolls, a family favorite since a 2000 dinner party. "We make them incessantly," says Zevnik. "That will be one of the first things I make when they get back" from Brosnan's overseas shoot for the next James Bond movie, Die Another Day. Until then Zevnik, who is single, has plenty to do in his Burbank abode. "I cook three-and four-course meals for myself," he says. "Who better to appreciate it?"

Fresh Crab Spring Rolls

1 lb. Dungeness crabmeat 1 tbsp. Star of Siam Thai oil* 1 tsp. black sesame seeds 1 ripe papaya, peeled, seeded &amp; sliced thin 1 green mango, peeled &amp; sliced thin handful of fresh chives, cut into 3-in. lengths 1 small jicama, peeled &amp; cut into 3-in. matchsticks 1 3-in. piece daikon (Japanese radish), peeled &amp; cut into matchsticks handful of fresh cilantro leaves handful of fresh edible blossoms package of rice flour spring roll wrappers* (*these items may be found in Asian markets)

Place crabmeat in small bowl. Add 1 tbsp. Thai oil and 1 tsp. black sesame seeds and toss lightly. Set aside. In a large bowl of hot water, soak one rice wrapper until pliable but still strong. Place wrapper on a large plate. Place a few edible blossoms on the wrapper, just below the centerline. Add a few cilantro leaves, about 1 heaping tbsp. of the crabmeat mixture, two pieces each of the papaya and the mango, then three sticks each of the chives, jicama and daikon. Lift the edge of the wrapper closest to you over the filling, pressing the ingredients together. Fold in an edge on either side, then gently roll up the wrapper to make a little package. Place on a large dish, covering with a damp tea towel. Repeat until all the crab has been used. If not serving immediately, keep rolls refrigerated and covered.

To serve: Slice rolls in half. Serve w/ teriyaki or Thai-style dipping sauce. Garnish with sliced oranges and fresh cilantro or mint. Serves 6-8

How To Get Super Fit Spider-Man Tobey Maguire went from soft to solid in six months. Could you? Greg Joujon-Roche, founder of Holistic Fitness, the L.A. health studio where Maguire trained, says you don't need a star's time and money to get into tip-top shape. Here's what Maguire did and what you can do.

REEL-LIFE ROUTINE

WORKOUT Maguire exercised for at least 3 ½ hours, six days a week, with his regimen varying "depending on how sore he felt," says Joujon-Roche. Mornings were spent improving his flexibility with yoga and splits, along with building strength through abdominal and lower-body exercises on an oversize ball. "We would just work on each body part until we killed it," Joujon-Roche says. "Then the next day we'd go to another and kill that one." Afternoons were devoted to cardiovascular activities like martial arts and cycling, to burn fat, plus gymnastics. "Tobey did his own flips with that Spider-Man hood on," says Joujon-Roche. "We gave him self-assuredness."

DIET For breakfast Joujon-Roche made the actor, a vegetarian, "a high-protein shake that included nuts, essential oils and vitamins." Lunch, he says, was often "marinated tofu with broccoli and walnuts and dinner a big veggie burger with brown rice." The menu varied with Maguire's output. "If his workout was pure weights," says Joujon-Roche, "he needed protein. If he did cardio, he'd have a shake of all carbs."

REAL-LIFE APPROACH

WORKOUT "Give yourself an hour a day," Joujon-Roche advises. "Women especially should do walking lunges and rear dips [which work the triceps]—as many as you can for as long as you can." He also recommends devoting at least half of every workout to cardiovascular activities such as swimming or running. "Pick a muscle group you want to address and really address it," says Joujon-Roche. "The biggest mistake for someone who wants six-pack [abs]," he adds, "is doing 500 sit-ups. Do 20 and feel the muscle. And when in doubt, breathe." As for his top tip, Joujon Roche says, "I'm not a gym person. I say, Get out into nature!"

DIET Oatmeal and fruit are a good idea for breakfast, Joujon-Roche says, while a big, dark-green salad topped with lean protein (such as 4 oz. of chicken or fish) will keep your energy up around lunchtime. For snacks he suggests munching on a handful of almonds or walnuts before having lean protein and "a ton" of vegetables for dinner. And one more thing: "Hydrate, hydrate, hydrate!" Joujon-Roche says. "You can't drink enough water."

Written by: Galina Espinoza, Jason Lynch, Sophfronia Scott Reported by: K C Baker, Amy Baumgartner, Carrie Bell, Rachel Biermann, Michelle Bowers, Karen Brailsford, Lauren Comander, Rachel Felder, Laura Sanderson Healy, Rosemary Jones, Julie Jordan, Lyneka Little, Susan Mandel, N.F. Mendoza, Colleen O'Connor, Dina Pinos, Debbie Seaman, John Slania

[This article contains a table. Please see hardcopy of magazine or PDF.]</TEXT>
<Meta /><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="1472" endPos="1475" type="person" surface="she">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="80_3" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="1" startPos="1518" endPos="1533" type="person" surface="Stephen Crisman">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="126_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="2" startPos="1562" endPos="1565" type="person" surface="she">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="27_3" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H." /></Entity>
<Entity id="3" startPos="1647" endPos="1651" type="person" surface="Dree">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="112_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="4" startPos="1661" endPos="1668" type="person" surface="Langley">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="126_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="5" startPos="3983" endPos="3986" type="person" surface="her">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="67_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="6" startPos="4002" endPos="4013" type="person" surface="Adam Beason">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="86_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="7" startPos="4228" endPos="4231" type="person" surface="her">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="4_4" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H." /></Entity>
<Entity id="8" startPos="4232" endPos="4236" type="date" surface="1998">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="8_2" />
<feature featureName="date_year" featureValue="1998" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="9" startPos="4259" endPos="4278" type="person" surface="Christopher Harvest">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="35_3" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="10" startPos="6067" endPos="6082" type="person" surface="Jayne Mansfield">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="39_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="11" startPos="6107" endPos="6122" type="person" surface="Mickey Hargitay">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="79_3" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="12" startPos="6128" endPos="6136" type="person" surface="Hargitay">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="100_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="13" startPos="13257" endPos="13260" type="person" surface="her">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="9_5" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="14" startPos="13269" endPos="13274" type="person" surface="Steve">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="21_3" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="15" startPos="13305" endPos="13311" type="person" surface="Connie">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="57_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="16" startPos="21412" endPos="21416" type="person" surface="Dion">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="0_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="17" startPos="21429" endPos="21441" type="person" surface="René Angélil">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="17_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="18" startPos="23194" endPos="23208" type="person" surface="Pierce Brosnan">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="12_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="19" startPos="23218" endPos="23235" type="person" surface="Keely Shaye Smith">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="36_3" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="20" startPos="23896" endPos="23901" type="person" surface="Dylan">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="123_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="21" startPos="23923" endPos="23928" type="person" surface="Paris">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="150_3" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H." /></Entity></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="22" NAME="marriage">
<Entity id="1" label="person" />
<Entity id="0" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="V.M., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc145_1392_1_308" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="23" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="3" label="person" />
<Entity id="4" label="person" />
<Entity id="2" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc145_1535_1_317" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="24" NAME="sibling_relationship">
<Entity id="3" label="person" />
<Entity id="4" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc145_1535_0_320" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="25" NAME="marriage">
<Entity id="5" label="person" />
<Entity id="6" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc145_3916_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="26" NAME="marriage">
<Entity id="7" label="person" />
<Entity id="9" label="person" />
<Entity id="8" label="from" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc145_4224_0_314" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="27" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="12" label="person" />
<Entity id="10" label="parent" />
<Entity id="11" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc145_6028_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="28" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="13" label="person" />
<Entity id="15" label="parent" />
<Entity id="14" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="V.M., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc145_13248_1_314" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="29" NAME="marriage">
<Entity id="16" label="person" />
<Entity id="17" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc145_21412_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="30" NAME="marriage">
<Entity id="18" label="person" />
<Entity id="19" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc145_23182_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="31" NAME="sibling_relationship">
<Entity id="21" label="person" />
<Entity id="20" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc145_23773_0_321" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
