<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Beyoncé Knowles: The Showstopper

SHE NEVER MISSES WHEN IT COMES TO DRESSING LIKE A DREAMGIRL—ON AND OFF THE RED CARPET

ELEMENTS OF STYLE

• Mix Things Up "<NODE id="157" />Beyoncé<NODE id="164" /> absolutely loves fashion, and it's such a big part of her life," says mom and stylist <NODE id="251" />Tina Knowles<NODE id="263" />. "In her personal time she is eclectic, but I wouldn't call her trendy. She follows trends, but they don't define her style—she's very sophisticated and classic."

• Always Look Put Together Whether she's dancing onstage or strolling in Saint-Tropez, she's always camera ready. "Even when she's in sweatpants <NODE id="573" />she<NODE id="576" /> puts on a heel and a really nice necklace and cool earrings," says <NODE id="644" />Mama Knowles<NODE id="656" />. The consistency applies to handbags as well: "She's a purse fanatic—she's trying to buy every new handbag that comes out."

• Dress For Your Shape B makes the most of her curvy figure, passing on last season's trendy loose babydolls in favor of fitted, waist-defining ensembles. And the vivid colors and sparkly metallics she chooses add to the eye-catching effect.

Get Beyoncé's Look!

ALL THE RAGE ONLINE Earrings, $16; 212-736-4586.

NEWPORT NEWS Yellow snap-front jacket, $64; newport-news.com.

SIMPLY VERA VERA WANG White poplin blouse, $54; kohls.com.

ARDEN B. Cream tapered pants (style #38248917), $88; ardenb.com.

NINE WEST Gold leather slingback sandals, $69; piperlime.com.

Cameron Diaz: The Legs

Get Cameron's Look!EXPRESS Black strapless minidress, $69.50; 877-415-4551.

ARDEN B. Metallic bejeweled clutch, $78; ardenb.com.

ELEMENTS OF STYLE • Glamour starts at the gym "She's got an incredible body, but she works at it," says trainer Teddy Bass, who keeps her legs in mini-worthy shape with squats and lunges.

• It's all in the details Distinctive accessories—a studded clutch, oversize rings—lend her outfits an unexpected edge.

ALL THE RAGE ONLINE Silver cuff, $15; alltherageonline.com. CLAIRE'S Star dangle ring, $6.50; claires.com for stores.

WET SEAL Silver metallic pumps, $22.50; wetseal.com.

Katie Holmes: The Classic

AMERICAN EAGLE Plastic frame sunglasses, $19.50; ae.com.

SPIEGEL Gold silk charmeuse tie-neck top, $59; spiegel.com.

DOCKERS Keyhole knit top, $36; dockers.com for more info.

GAP Black jeans, $59.50; gap.com for stores.

Get Katie's Look!

RAMPAGE White canvas bag, $98; spiegel.com.

TARGET Patent leather moccasins, $22.99; 800-800-8800 for stores.

WHAT A YEAR! SHE SHED HER GIRLY IMAGE, CUT HER HAIR—AND PERFECTED A REFINED AND TIMELESS LOOK

ELEMENTS OF STYLE

• Understatement Can Speak Volumes "Katie embodies the highest concept of class," says friend Roberta Armani (whose uncle Giorgio designed Holmes's wedding gown). "She is a modern Jackie Onassis—a real lady and an iconic beauty."

• Tailoring Is Key Holmes's clothing may seem uncomplicated, but the fit is impeccable. The star's style displays "a sharp simplicity but is very chic," says designer Giambattista Valli, who hosted Holmes at his Paris show last fall. "She looks fabulous, but you see her first, then the clothes."

• Stick With What Works So what if she towers over Tom? Holmes is not one to abandon her heels completely. "Her style is evolving," says Valli. "She's becoming more elegant and more confident."

Penélope Cruz: The Continental

Get Penélope's Look! XOXO Plastic frame sunglasses, $35; xoxo.com.

ELEMENTS OF STYLE

• Know when to go wild Cruz always goes for "the most dramatic thing," says Estee Stanley, who styles her with Cristina Ehrlich. "She'll put on the biggest dress on the planet and rock it!"

• And when to keep it simple Her casual clothes are classic and feminine.

METROSTYLE Knit dress, $49.99; metrostyle.com.

H&amp;M Belt with rhinestone buckle, $7.90; hm.com for stores.

CHARLOTTE RUSSE Black patent slingback heels, $22.99; 866-896-7568.

In Dior Haute Couture by John Galliano at the Golden Globes.

In Roberto Cavalli in Los Angeles.

In Versace in Beverly Hills.

Drew Barrymore: The Chameleon

MODERN GLAMOUR ONE DAY AND RETRO CHIC THE NEXT, SHE'S MASTERED THE ART OF BEING ECLECTIC

ELEMENTS OF STYLE

• Follow Your Heart You'll never see this Hollywood veteran get into a style rut: "Just keep taking risks and going for it, and don't play it safe . . . don't dress for what you think someone else will like," says Barrymore about her fashion philosophy. And it doesn't just apply to her clothes: Whether she rocks stick-straight hair and natural makeup or sultry eyes and an updo, Barrymore takes a look and works it head to toe. But somehow, it never comes across as high maintenance. "Her style is comfortably chic," says CoverGirl makeup artist Molly R. Stern, who's prettified the star.

• Break The Rules Though her dresses are full-on glamorous, Barrymore always adds a bit of a rock-star edge with embellished necklines, dramatic makeup or chunky, eye-catching jewelry. Says Stern: "We have watched her grow into a sophisticated woman who still has traces of her funky youth."

GIRLPROPS Stud earrings, $2.99; 212-505-7615.

VICTORIA'S SECRET CATALOGUE Black French cuff blouse, $39; victoriassecret.com.

NEW YORK &amp; COMPANY Black pencil skirt, $29.95; nyandcompany.com.

DEVI KROELL FOR TARGET Faux snake box clutch, $29.99; target.com for stores.

CLAIRE'S Pavé crystal ring in gold, $9.50; claires.com.

Get Drew's Look!

BANDOLINO Patent Mary Jane pumps, $79; 800-999-1877 for stores.

Jessica Biel: The All-American

Get Jessica's Look!

ELEMENTS OF STYLE

• Easy does it Biel chooses gowns that look "elegant, but not like she's trying too hard," says Estee Stanley, who, along with Cristina Ehrlich, styles the star.

• Play to your strengths Biel knows what suits her strong frame: fitted silhouettes in solid colors.

H&amp;M Grey graphic tank, $19.90; hm.com for stores.

LEVI'S Low Flare Jean, $68; levistore.com.

PAYLESS Black patent buckle flat, $19.99; payless.com for stores.

Jennifer Lopez: The Glamour Girl

PARTIAL TO GLITZY GOWNS, BOLD JEWELRY AND HIP-HUGGING JEANS, SHE ALWAYS DRESSES TO MAKE AN ENTRANCE

ELEMENTS OF STYLE

• Play Up Your Assets She's got hips, and she flaunts them in form-fitting gowns, tight jeans and color-blocked dresses that show off her fab hour-glass figure.

• Rock The Accessories As with any diva, diamonds are this girl's best friend. She's often decked out in dazzling Lorraine Schwartz jewelry or her signature oversize gold or silver hoops and an armful of stacked bangles.

• Make A Strong Statement "Jennifer is a true beauty," says her makeup artist Scott Barnes. "She always steps into her power as a woman, no matter what she's wearing."

• Be Inspired This season Lopez has been sporting '70s looks similar to her El Cantante character, favoring wide-leg jeans, high-waisted pants and plenty of chunky platform heels.

ICING BY CLAIRE'S Silver hoop earrings, $8; icingbyclaires.com for stores.

SPIEGEL Animal print tunic, $59; spiegel.com.

AMERICAN EAGLE Stretch trouser jean, $49.50; ae.com.

Get Jennifer's Look!

MOSSIMO FOR TARGET Faux-croc tote, $29.99; 800-800-8800 for stores.

TRIBECA BY KENNETH COLE Black platform heel, $60; piperlime.com.

ALL THE RAGE ONLINE Assorted silver bangles, $10--$24; alltherageonline.com.

Reese Witherspoon: The Celeb Next Door

ELEMENTS OF STYLE

•Be consistent Olivier Theyskens, who outfitted Witherspoon throughout the awards season, says, "She is the embodiment of a strong, modern woman."

• Less is more Fitted pieces flatter Reese's petite frame on and off the red carpet.

Get Reese's Look!

H&amp;M sunglasses, $6.90; hm.com for stores.

OLD NAVY Black trapeze dress, $29.50; oldnavy.com.

APT. 9 Black lace top, $34; kohls.com for stores.

EXPRESS Clover necklace, $24.50; expressfashion.com for stores.

ACCESSORIES Black bag, $19.99; kmart.com for stores.

MIA Black leather skimmer flat, $60; piperlime.com.

Gwen Stefani: The Trendsetter

COMBINING HIGH FASHION WITH STREET CHIC AND FUN ACCENTS (ANIMAL PRINTS, ANYONE?), SHE ALWAYS ROCKS

ELEMENTS OF STYLE

• Have No Fear "There have been times that she's been on red carpet when she definitely pushes the envelope," says singer and pal Eve. "What makes Gwen an icon is she makes up her own rules." Which others are more than happy to follow: Her L.A.M.B. clothing and accessories line is one of the bestselling celeb brands.

• Embrace Patterns. Stefani loves animal prints, plaids, camouflage and stripes—and isn't afraid to mix them in the same outfit. While the look isn't for the faint of heart, the star makes sure that the prints are balanced by proportioned silhouettes.

• Red Lipstick Goes With Everything Whether she's in sweats or in a glamorous gown, Gwen rarely goes without her signature fire-engine-red lipstick. So how many tubes are in Stefani's makeup bag? "Way too many to count," she confesses.

FASHION BUG Leopard wrap dress, $29.99; fashionbug.com.

URBAN OUTFITTERS Black leather belt with gold buckle, $24; urbanoutfitters.com for stores.

ALL THE RAGE ONLINE Gold bangle with black stones, $24; 212-736-4586.

ARDEN B. Black chunky ring, $18; ardenb.com for stores.

Get Gwen's Look!

NINE WEST Black patent leather and suede platform heel, $89; ninewest.com.

Ali Larter: The Newcomer

Get Ali's Look!

ELEMENTS OF STYLE

• Feel good "Comfort is key," says the Heroes actress. "I like things that are loose but hug in all the right places."

• Keep it basic Larter avoids "really busy" patterns in favor of solid colors.

• Stand tall! "I never feel more powerful than when I'm in a 4-in. heel."

LOVE TEASE halter top, $49; 323-584-4400.

BANANA REPUBLIC Martin stretch pant, $88; bananarepublic.com.

ALL THE RAGE ONLINE Black plastic inlay bangle, $40; alltherageonline.com.

CHINESE LAUNDRY Gold leather heeled sandals, $60; piperlime.com.</TEXT>
<Meta /><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="157" endPos="164" type="person" surface="Beyoncé">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="17_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="1" startPos="251" endPos="263" type="person" surface="Tina Knowles">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="111_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="2" startPos="573" endPos="576" type="person" surface="she">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="31_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H." /></Entity>
<Entity id="3" startPos="644" endPos="656" type="person" surface="">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="102" /></Entity></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="4" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="0" label="person" />
<Entity id="1" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc3_140_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="5" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="2" label="person" />
<Entity id="3" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc3_542_0_87" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
