<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Cyndi Lauper, as the world well knows, is a girl who just wants to have fun. So when, a few years back, the Grammy-award-winning singer got the chance to open for Cher on her sold-out Believe tour, Lauper didn't think twice: Pop's punk princess packed up her guitar, her purple minidress and, oh yes, <NODE id="301" />her<NODE id="304" /> 18-month-old son <NODE id="322" />Declyn<NODE id="328" />. The only thing she forgot, it turns out, was her better judgment. "It was terrible," says Lauper, 48, of her three-month stint playing rock-star mom. "I was on the bus trying to pump and nurse and the kid is being knocked around. Every time the bus moves a little, you move a lot. I thought I could drag him all over with me," she says, "but it wasn't working out."

And so, Lauper came to the realization that sooner or later hits every working mother who has passed up a plum job to be with her child: You can't have it all (or, at least, not all at the same time). In a world where performers target the glow of stardom with the determination of heat-seeking missiles, an increasingly long list of the biggest names in showbiz—including Celine Dion, Demi Moore, Annette Bening and Jodie Foster—no longer want to. In the enviable financial position to be able to Just Say No, some celebs, such as former MTV whiz kid Tabitha Soren, give up working altogether. Others, including Sissy Spacek—who took a break from life on her Virginia farm to film her Oscar-nominated turn in In the Bedroom—just slow down. Whatever the logistics, though, the logic is the same.

"At the end of the day it's about women wanting balance," says producer Lynda Obst, who got Bening to star in 1998's The Siege with offers of on-set daycare and a special play trailer for her kids. "What it feels like is, 'I'm not going on 100 percent psycho-drive just to get work, work, work. I'm only going to do the stuff that has value because I love my family and I'm just as happy staying home as working.' "

Happier, even. Single mom and Panic Room star Foster, 39, recently closed down Egg Pictures, her 12-year-old production company, and tries to limit herself to acting in one film every two years. As she told Premiere in March of <NODE id="2139" />her<NODE id="2142" /> desire to spend time with sons <NODE id="2174" />Charles<NODE id="2181" />, 3, and <NODE id="2190" />Kit<NODE id="2193" />, 6 months, "Raising them is so much more interesting than anything else I do."

That may be easy for Foster to say, having acted in almost three dozen movies, directed two others (Little Man Tate and Home for the Holidays) and won two Best Actress Oscars (for 1988's The Accused and 1991's The Silence of the Lambs), Indeed, what Foster craves most now is an ordinary life. Some actors pay someone to "walk their dog and pick up the kids from school," she said. "But that's your life. So you're paying someone else to live your life so you can work more? I'd rather pay somebody to work for me." For her, motherhood is "the great equalizer," says her former producing partner and fellow parent Julie Bergman Sender. "We're all at the park in our T-shirts that have a million food stains on them, and it doesn't matter if you're a working mother, a stay-at-home mom or an Academy Award-winning actress. Everybody is in there making sure her kid isn't eating sand—and that includes Jodie."

Of course, Foster's $15 million-a-picture paychecks give her the freedom to choose, a luxury only a relative few can afford. "I never had the option of saying, 'I think I'll stop and do carpool and knit,' " says Lynda Obst, whose son is now 23. Still, as mothers on both ends of the salary scale know, working is often not entirely about payday; it is also about identity—a mind-set that is generally age-related, says producer Peter Guber. "Actresses in their 20s live to work," he says. "Those over 30 work to live. The vagaries of the business become so prominent that family takes on greater importance." Especially established stars, he says, "realize, 'Been there, did it.' "

Timing certainly was an issue for Demi Moore, 39. Over the course of two years starting in 1996, the actress with more than $1 billion in box office sales to her name saw her life turned upside down. After receiving a then-record $12.5 million to star in Striptease, she withstood withering criticism when it tanked. The following year's G.I. Jane proved another disappointment. Then, in <NODE id="4254" />June of 1998<NODE id="4266" />, <NODE id="4268" />her<NODE id="4271" /> 10-year marriage to <NODE id="4292" />Bruce Willis<NODE id="4304" /> collapsed—and a month later she watched as <NODE id="4348" />her<NODE id="4351" /> long-estranged mother, <NODE id="4375" />Virginia Guynes<NODE id="4390" />, died of a brain tumor and cancer at age 54. <NODE id="4436" />Moore<NODE id="4441" /> holed up in her mountain hamlet of Hailey, Idaho, to play full-time mom to daughters <NODE id="4527" />Rumer<NODE id="4532" />, now 13, <NODE id="4542" />Scout<NODE id="4547" />, 10, and <NODE id="4557" />Tallulah<NODE id="4565" />, 8. "I just needed to stop and take a break," she told In STYLE. "The gains outweigh any losses." Today her greatest pleasure seems to be sitting in the audience, as she did a few months ago at nearby Ketchum's St. Thomas Episcopal Church—alongside her ex as well as her beau of three years, martial arts instructor Oliver Whitcomb, 31—watching Rumer sing solo with the Sun Valley Summer Symphony.

"I think there's a natural cycle in a woman's life that is somewhat in tune with her body," says three-time Oscar nominee <NODE id="5087" />Debra Winger<NODE id="5099" />, 48, who captivated audiences in such '80s mega—hits as An Officer and a Gentleman and Terms of Endearment before bolting from the spotlight six years ago to raise three boys: <NODE id="5276" />Babe<NODE id="5280" />, 4, <NODE id="5285" />her<NODE id="5288" /> son with actor-director husband <NODE id="5321" />Arliss Howard<NODE id="5334" />, 47; <NODE id="5340" />Noah<NODE id="5344" />, 14 (with ex-husband actor <NODE id="5372" />Timothy Hutton<NODE id="5386" />); and stepson <NODE id="5401" />Sam<NODE id="5404" />, also 14. "You look at your life and say, 'Do I want to do the same thing for the second half that I did for the first? I feel different. Maybe I should be different.' "

For some the revelation is swift and painless. After spending 13 years as a favorite of American audiences on such TV shows as General Hospital and Dynasty, <NODE id="5733" />Emma Samms<NODE id="5743" />, 41, fell in love with psychiatrist and fellow <NODE id="5791" />Brit John Holloway<NODE id="5809" />, now 43, and promptly relocated to a home in the British countryside, where she cares for their son <NODE id="5910" />Cameron<NODE id="5917" />, 5, and daughter <NODE id="5935" />Bea<NODE id="5938" />, 4. Of her sudden desire to take only occasional parts that don't require long absences from home, she says, "There was no agonizing. If I was going to have children, I was going to raise them myself. It's just a matter of priorities." For Bening, 43, however, the initial stirrings of motherhood were more complex. "The first time I lost my desire to work <NODE id="6296" />I<NODE id="6297" /> was scared," the wife of <NODE id="6323" />Warren Beatty<NODE id="6336" />, who turns 65 on March 30, and mother to <NODE id="6378" />Kathlyn<NODE id="6385" />, 10, <NODE id="6391" />Ben<NODE id="6394" />, 7, <NODE id="6399" />Isabel<NODE id="6405" />, 4, and <NODE id="6414" />Ella<NODE id="6418" />, 1, told Good Housekeeping in 2000. "I thought, 'Is this going to go away and not come back?' Now I realize there's an ebb and flow."

And fortunately for her—as well as her fellow A-listers—an industry that's willing to go with the flow. "These stars have tenacious agents who are able to carve out for them a set that is user-friendly, whether it's extra security or air transportation for the nanny and kids," says Guber. "There is no perk today that is beyond the imaginations of the agents. The only one you can't do is put the baby back in." That was never an issue for Bening. Indeed, what allowed her to pull off her Oscar-nominated portrayal of an ambition-crazed mother in 1999's American Beauty was her ability to be just the opposite offscreen.

"Once while we were setting up an exterior scene she was over on the grass under a tree with all of her kids," recalls Beauty screenwriter Alan Ball. "She took off her high heels, put on her tennis shoes and played tag with them. She was having so much fun, she was completely unaware of this movie company 200 feet away. I thought, 'Gee, I wish my mom had done this.' "

Still, as Tabitha Soren has discovered, motherhood is not always splendor in the grass. A Manhattan-based reporter for MTV, she made her name interviewing Bill Clinton and Yasser Arafat before she turned 30. But after marrying <NODE id="7776" />Michael Lewis<NODE id="7789" />, now 41, author of the bestselling Next: The Future Just Happened, and giving birth to daughter <NODE id="7886" />Quinn<NODE id="7891" /> in 1999, <NODE id="7901" />she<NODE id="7904" /> decided to abandon the glam life and relocate to "family-friendly Berkeley," says Soren, now 34 and eight months pregnant with baby No. 2. But even there, the couple have been taken aback by what Lewis calls the "status collapse" caused by Soren's decision to be a full-time parent. "At dinner parties people are a lot less interested in what she is doing now," says Lewis. "I'm surprised it hasn't dealt Tabitha more of a blow."

Maybe that's because part of her understands the desire to flee at the first mention of sing-alongs—which is why Soren takes time off every Saturday to go to photography class. "I can only play with Legos for so long," she says. "Our society gives a lot of lip service to the idea of motherhood being so good," she adds. "But at the end of the day, people still say to me, 'Besides taking care of Quinn, what else do you do?' America is much more about money, ambition and status. I have been all those things. I am just not those things right now."

Like guests at those parties, Hollywood has mixed feelings about its Maternal Girls. Casting director Lisa Mae Fincannon (Dawson's Creek) feels the industry is so all-consuming, "it's like your mistress," she says. "You literally have to leave it to make your family life complete." A side benefit: The time off can improve your acting, as, she believes, the years <NODE id="9252" />Sissy Spacek<NODE id="9264" />, 52, has devoted to raising daughters <NODE id="9303" />Schuyler<NODE id="9311" />, 19, and <NODE id="9321" />Madison<NODE id="9328" />, 13, did. "One of my husband's comments after seeing her performance in In the Bedroom," she says, "was 'Boy, has life given her a lot to work with.' "

Still, all that living doesn't pay the salary of those tenacious handlers who drive a star's career. Just ask Martina McBride, 35. At first the births of Delaney, 7, and Emma, 3, didn't stop the multi-platinum-selling country music star. She and <NODE id="9728" />her<NODE id="9731" /> husband, <NODE id="9741" />John<NODE id="9745" />, 44, equipped a bus with a crib, a cooktop and a washer and dryer and just figured, McBride says, "life will go on as normal." And except for the odd show performed with "spit-up from my wrist to my elbow," she says, it did. But as her girls got older, McBride did not want to take them out of school to tour with her—or leave home without them. Her decision to tour only during school breaks still causes friction, she says. "[My business people] have said to me, 'Why don't you leave them at home? It's just four days,' " says McBride. "I say, 'Because I'm the mommy.' "

Like McBride, Celine Dion, 33, has the power to call the shots—including telling the family's chef, Bernard Goupy, that she would be the one baking the chocolate cake for <NODE id="10491" />her<NODE id="10494" /> son <NODE id="10499" />Rene-Charles<NODE id="10511" />'s first birthday on Jan. 25. "Every little cough, she calls the doctor," says Goupy. "She is a mother 24 hours a day." Which is why, two years after taking what she called a "temporary retirement" to conceive her son, Dion and <NODE id="10739" />her<NODE id="10742" /> manager husband, <NODE id="10760" />Rene Angélil<NODE id="10772" />, 60, have signed a three-year deal with Caesars Palace in Las Vegas for a reported $100 million. Building a home nearby, Dion will be able to put her boy to bed before going to work five nights a week, and be asleep early enough to be rested for patty-cake the next day.

That Dion was one of the world's top-selling recording artists when she dropped out paved the way for her comeback. "Hollywood is career first and family second," says casting director Ellen Jacoby. "If an actor is not fairly successful, taking time off will hurt."

Judging from the fate of Rosanna Arquette, 42, even if she is successful, there are no guarantees. In 1994, after the birth of <NODE id="11439" />her<NODE id="11442" /> daughter <NODE id="11452" />Zoe<NODE id="11455" /> (with ex-husband record exec <NODE id="11485" />Jon Sidel<NODE id="11494" />, 40), the star of the 1985 hit Desperately Seeking Susan decided to work less. But when she was ready to get back in the game in 1997, she was in for a shock. Arriving at Universal Studios for what she thought was a meeting with a major director, she was met instead by a casting agent who asked her to tape an audition. "She said, 'You know, they really want a movie star,' " Arquette recalls. "I left with tears streaming down my face, thinking, 'Oh my God, what has happened?' I said, 'Hi, I'm back.' And they said, 'Yeah? So? Who are you?' "

Spurred by her experience, as well as that of dozens of her female colleagues, Arquette has produced and directed a documentary called Searching for Debra Winger. The two actresses met last year while working on the just-released indie flick Big Bad Love, which Winger had agreed to star in and produce only because the movie's cowriter, director and costar is her husband. Arquette made her own film because, she said, "I wanted to know why Debra Winger, a truly amazing actress, left the business."

Winger's answer: "I have three boys. That's a full-time job." Most days she can be found at home in Westchester County, N.Y., where, Winger says, "I wake up, figure out what we should defrost for dinner and do all this running around." The scenario probably sounds familiar to Spacek. As she recently told Newsweek, "I don't know how the rumor started that I had retired. I just had children, and you know how children are—you've got to take care of them."

As for whether an actress works a little, a lot or not at all, says Dr. Joyce Brothers, "as long as Mama wants to do what she's doing, the kids love it"—assuming, of course, that in "whatever time she does have, she is interacting with and caring about the child."

That has been Cyndi Lauper's experience since bolting the tour bus. At home in Manhattan, the musician and <NODE id="13375" />her<NODE id="13378" /> actor husband, <NODE id="13394" />David Thornton<NODE id="13408" />, 47 (John Q.), have the help of a full-time nanny but still spend lots of time with Dec, now 4, ice-skating and listening to him bang the drums. "Our son is gifted," says Lauper—which is one reason good mothering to her means not giving up her career. "I want him to know that everyone has that thing that makes them feel more alive." Next winter, she plans to hit the road to promote her as-yet-untitled new album, flying home between gigs to tell her son all about it. "I'm trying to have my cake and eat it too," says Lauper. "But not too much cake."

Karen S. Schneider Reported by: Robyn Flans, Julie Jordan and Vicki Sheff-Cahan in Los Angeles, KC Baker and Caroline Howard in New York City, Beverly Keel in Nashville, Linda Marx and Don Sider in West Palm Beach, Laura Morice in Charlotte, Keith Raether in Hailey and Ellin Stein in London</TEXT>
<Meta /><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="301" endPos="304" type="person" surface="her">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="224_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="1" startPos="322" endPos="328" type="person" surface="Declyn">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="245_4" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="2" startPos="2139" endPos="2142" type="person" surface="her">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="33_4" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H." /></Entity>
<Entity id="3" startPos="2174" endPos="2181" type="person" surface="Charles">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="68_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="4" startPos="2190" endPos="2193" type="person" surface="Kit">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="84_3" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="5" startPos="4254" endPos="4266" type="date" surface="June of 1998">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="9_1" />
<feature featureName="date_year" featureValue="1998" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="date_month" featureValue="June" /></Entity>
<Entity id="6" startPos="4268" endPos="4271" type="person" surface="her">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="23_4" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="7" startPos="4292" endPos="4304" type="person" surface="Bruce Willis">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="47_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="8" startPos="4348" endPos="4351" type="person" surface="her">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="103_3" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="9" startPos="4375" endPos="4390" type="person" surface="Virginia Guynes">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="130_5" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="10" startPos="4436" endPos="4441" type="person" surface="Moore">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="0_4" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="11" startPos="4527" endPos="4532" type="person" surface="Rumer">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="91_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="12" startPos="4542" endPos="4547" type="person" surface="Scout">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="106_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="13" startPos="4557" endPos="4565" type="person" surface="Tallulah">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="121_3" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="14" startPos="5087" endPos="5099" type="person" surface="Debra Winger">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="122_5" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="15" startPos="5276" endPos="5280" type="person" surface="Babe">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="311_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="16" startPos="5285" endPos="5288" type="person" surface="her">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="320_4" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="17" startPos="5321" endPos="5334" type="person" surface="Arliss Howard">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="356_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="18" startPos="5340" endPos="5344" type="person" surface="Noah">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="375_7" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="19" startPos="5372" endPos="5386" type="person" surface="Timothy Hutton">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="407_6" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="20" startPos="5401" endPos="5404" type="person" surface="Sam">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="436_3" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="21" startPos="5733" endPos="5743" type="person" surface="Emma Samms">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="110_3" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="22" startPos="5791" endPos="5809" type="person" surface="">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="168" /></Entity>
<Entity id="23" startPos="5910" endPos="5917" type="person" surface="Cameron">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="287_4" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="24" startPos="5935" endPos="5938" type="person" surface="Bea">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="312_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="25" startPos="6296" endPos="6297" type="person" surface="I">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="41_6" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="26" startPos="6323" endPos="6336" type="person" surface="Warren Beatty">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="68_5" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="27" startPos="6378" endPos="6385" type="person" surface="Kathlyn">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="123_8" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="28" startPos="6391" endPos="6394" type="person" surface="Ben">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="136_4" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="29" startPos="6399" endPos="6405" type="person" surface="Isabel">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="144_3" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="30" startPos="6414" endPos="6418" type="person" surface="Ella">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="159_7" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="31" startPos="7776" endPos="7789" type="person" surface="Michael Lewis">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="19_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="32" startPos="7886" endPos="7891" type="person" surface="Quinn">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="129_4" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="33" startPos="7901" endPos="7904" type="person" surface="she">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="144_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="34" startPos="9252" endPos="9264" type="person" surface="Sissy Spacek">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="82_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="35" startPos="9303" endPos="9311" type="person" surface="Schuyler">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="133_3" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="36" startPos="9321" endPos="9328" type="person" surface="Madison">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="151_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="37" startPos="9728" endPos="9731" type="person" surface="her">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="8_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="38" startPos="9741" endPos="9745" type="person" surface="John">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="21_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="39" startPos="10491" endPos="10494" type="person" surface="her">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="171_5" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="40" startPos="10499" endPos="10511" type="person" surface="Rene-Charles">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="179_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="41" startPos="10739" endPos="10742" type="person" surface="her">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="108_4" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H." /></Entity>
<Entity id="42" startPos="10760" endPos="10772" type="person" surface="Rene Angélil">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="129_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="43" startPos="11439" endPos="11442" type="person" surface="her">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="28_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="44" startPos="11452" endPos="11455" type="person" surface="Zoe">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="41_3" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="45" startPos="11485" endPos="11494" type="person" surface="Jon Sidel">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="74_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="46" startPos="13375" endPos="13378" type="person" surface="her">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="39_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="47" startPos="13394" endPos="13408" type="person" surface="David Thornton">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="58_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="48" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="1" label="person" />
<Entity id="0" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_77_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="49" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="3" label="person" />
<Entity id="4" label="person" />
<Entity id="2" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_2106_1_228" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="50" NAME="sibling_relationship">
<Entity id="3" label="person" />
<Entity id="4" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_2106_0_239" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="51" NAME="marriage">
<Entity id="5" label="to" />
<Entity id="6" label="person" />
<Entity id="7" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_4245_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="52" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="8" label="person" />
<Entity id="9" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_4245_0_229" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="53" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="12" label="person" />
<Entity id="13" label="person" />
<Entity id="11" label="person" />
<Entity id="10" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_4436_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="54" NAME="sibling_relationship">
<Entity id="12" label="person" />
<Entity id="13" label="person" />
<Entity id="11" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_4436_2" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="55" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="18" label="person" />
<Entity id="19" label="parent" />
<Entity id="14" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_4965_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="56" NAME="marriage">
<Entity id="19" label="person" />
<Entity id="14" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_4965_2" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="57" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="15" label="person" />
<Entity id="17" label="parent" />
<Entity id="14" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_4965_1_232" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="58" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="15" label="person" />
<Entity id="16" label="parent" />
<Entity id="17" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="V.M., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_4965_4_226" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="59" NAME="sibling_relationship">
<Entity id="15" label="person" />
<Entity id="18" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_4965_0_241" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="60" NAME="marriage">
<Entity id="16" label="person" />
<Entity id="17" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_4965_2_220" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="61" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="20" label="person" />
<Entity id="14" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="V.M., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_4965_3_225" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="62" NAME="sibling_relationship">
<Entity id="23" label="person" />
<Entity id="24" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_5623_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="63" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="23" label="person" />
<Entity id="24" label="person" />
<Entity id="21" label="parent" />
<Entity id="22" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_5623_2" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="64" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="29" label="person" />
<Entity id="27" label="person" />
<Entity id="30" label="person" />
<Entity id="28" label="person" />
<Entity id="25" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_6255_1_234" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="65" NAME="sibling_relationship">
<Entity id="29" label="person" />
<Entity id="27" label="person" />
<Entity id="30" label="person" />
<Entity id="28" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="V.M., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_6255_4_235" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="66" NAME="marriage">
<Entity id="25" label="person" />
<Entity id="26" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_6255_0_221" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="67" NAME="marriage">
<Entity id="31" label="person" />
<Entity id="33" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="V.M., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_7757_2_215" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="68" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="32" label="person" />
<Entity id="33" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="V.M., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_7757_3_229" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="69" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="35" label="person" />
<Entity id="36" label="person" />
<Entity id="34" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_9170_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="70" NAME="sibling_relationship">
<Entity id="35" label="person" />
<Entity id="36" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_9170_0_243" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="71" NAME="marriage">
<Entity id="37" label="person" />
<Entity id="38" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_9720_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="72" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="40" label="person" />
<Entity id="39" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_10320_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="73" NAME="marriage">
<Entity id="41" label="person" />
<Entity id="42" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_10631_0_224" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="74" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="44" label="person" />
<Entity id="45" label="parent" />
<Entity id="43" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_11411_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="75" NAME="marriage">
<Entity id="45" label="person" />
<Entity id="43" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_11411_2" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="76" NAME="marriage">
<Entity id="47" label="person" />
<Entity id="46" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc48_13336_1" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
