<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Document>
<TEXT>Foolish is the man who would deny Julia Roberts. Apparently unaware of the actress's power to vaporize mortals with a flash of her smile, a manager at Manhattan's Tavern on the Green tried denying her a postparty bottle of champagne following the National Board of Review Awards on Jan. 16. Roberts, eager to continue toasting her best-actress award for Erin Brockovich, dispatched her bodyguard with a message: "She wants you to tell her that to her face." The manager regretfully informed the star that the bar was closed. "Ah, c'mon," Roberts teased, deploying the killer grin. "You're telling me that in all of Tavern on the Green, I can't get a glass of champagne? I'm celebrating!"

Zap! Poof! Vaporized. Another bottle of Cristal for the lady!

And while you're at it, you might want to polish that Oscar too. The first actress to gross more than $1 billion at the box office, Julia Fiona Roberts, 33, has become one Pretty-Powerful Woman. "As an investment," says Wall Street entertainment analyst Hal Vogel, "Standard &amp; Poor's would rate her triple-A."

Meaning that whether it's a $20 million paycheck, a back rub from her adoring boyfriend of 3½ years, Benjamin Bratt, or just another glass of champagne, what Julia wants, Julia gets. There are downsides, of course, to having that kind of clout. It's impossible, for example, to stroll with a friend without sparking rumors you're involved in a tryst. But you won't hear Roberts moan. "To complain about that," she says, "is to be like the fastest woman runner on the planet and complain about a blister. Yeah? So what? You're the fastest woman in the world."

Marion Jones has the Olympic gold medals to prove it, but Roberts is still looking for the Hollywood equivalent—a Best Actress Oscar—to put on the mantel, next to the Golden Globe and British Academy of Film and Television Arts awards she has already bagged for Erin Brockovich. Nominated twice before (as Best Supporting Actress for 1989's Steel Magnolias and as Best Actress for 1990's Pretty Woman), she might be excused if she feels her time has finally come with Brockovich, a meatier-than-usual dramatic role that won critical raves. "In terms of getting recognition from her peers, it would be a thrill," says Roberts's friend and Stepmom costar Susan Sarandon, who along with George Clooney (who dubbed Roberts "J. Ro"), Diane Sawyer and other stars toasted the actress at an American Museum of the Moving Image tribute in Manhattan March 4. Roberts, she said, has "an excellent chance" at winning.

Should she miss out, however, don't expect the kind of churlish behavior that earned a 23-year-old Roberts the nickname Tinkerhell on the set of I991's Hook. That Julia—the same clumsy ingenue who once checkered her career with dreary duds like Mary Reilly and tabloid sensations involving such beaus as ex-fiancé Kiefer Sutherland—is a distant memory. These days, says her longtime friend and former agent Elaine Goldsmith-Thomas, "Julia lives her life with ease and humor and grace."

And confidence. Lately Roberts hasn't been afraid to take professional risks. She waived her usual fee to costar with Brad Pitt in The Mexican, the $35 million caper flick from director Gore Verbinski, 36, whose credits to date include directing animatronic frogs in a Budweiser ad and the goofy 1997 comedy MouseHunt. In her next movie, America's Sweethearts, Roberts plays a gawky minion to a movie diva played by Catherine Zeta-Jones. Formula for a catfight? Forget it. "We have this banter. She imitates my accent," the Welsh beauty reports from the set. "We're having a lot of fun."

So where did all this equanimity come from? "It's 15 years of practice," says Roberts. "I'm older, I'm a grownup." Not to mention thoroughly loved up. As she told David Letterman on Feb. 19, "I don't have to win [the Oscar]. I have my own little golden man at home." How the 6'2" Bratt, 37, enjoyed that comparison is anyone's guess. The actor—who, since quitting NBC's Law &amp; Order in 1999, has costarred with Sandra Bullock in Miss Congeniality and had a cameo in Traffic—is so protective of the couple's privacy that "I'm like a grizzly bear," he recently told TV Guide.

Ask Roberts about him, however, and she sings like a canary. "He's the best reason to go home I can think of," she told the 700-plus guests at the AMMI tribute. "She's in love, ain't no doubt about it," adds Verbinski. "She always talks about him." Bakes him chocolate chip cookies too. Roberts even had a batch of her best mailed overnight last March to Belize—where Bratt was filming the USA Network movie After the Storm—before flying in for a five-day visit spent reading, jogging and snuggling with her man.

Bratt may be quieter about it, but the devotion is mutual. Dining at L.A.'s posh Ivy restaurant on Jan. 20, the night before the Golden Globes, the couple held hands throughout dinner and "looked very peaceful and very much in love," reports a fellow patron.

Not so peaceful are the paparazzi, who will go to any lengths for the juice on Julia. Director Garry Marshall recalls huddling with Roberts on the Berlin, Md., set of 1999's Runaway Bride, when the actress broke off with a start and blurted—accurately—"There's a photographer in the tree!" Photographs of her walk in the park with ex-boyfriend Jason Patric in Los Angeles last summer set off fevered speculation that Roberts and Bratt were on the rocks.

Next thing you knew, they were on their honeymoon. "Somebody told me the other day that I got married three weeks ago in Vegas and that Erin Brockovich was my maid of honor," Roberts deadpanned to USA Today last month. For the record, she and Bratt, who both wear friendship rings, have no plans to wed. "Why would anyone want to get married?" Roberts said jokingly in IN STYLE this month. "We're just happy, we're just cruising. But if that changes..."

You can forgive the fascination with Roberts—if not the falsehoods. If the lady is beguiling from afar, up close, say friends, she is bewitching. On the set of Bride, "people asked Richard [Gere] for his autograph and they asked me for a job," says Marshall. "But with Julia they were struck dumb. Some had tears in their eyes. The only other time I saw that was with Princess Diana."

Hard to believe that the woman emitting all that radiance could also be the buffoon you hear in the back of the theater guffawing above everyone else. "If you go to a movie with her and it's a comedy, watch out!" says Goldsmith-Thomas. "The first time we went to see Pretty Woman, she was laughing at herself. Richard Gere and [his agent] Ed Limato were sitting in the back, and she was cracking up louder than anyone. I was like, 'Keep it down!"

Fat chance. If there is one thing that Roberts lacks, it's pretense. "Don't kid yourself," she told the adoring AMMI audience, "there are plenty of people who don't like me." She does her own grocery shopping and cleans her own Manhattan apartment. When she has to dress up, she chooses her own clothes, often classics like Armani and Calvin Klein. (Says Goldsmith-Thomas: "It would never occur to her to have a stylist.") What's more, she's just as comfortable in the company of gaffers and best boys as she is with the red-carpet crowd. "She remembers their names," says Brockovich director Steven Soderbergh. "She will ask about the wife and kids."

While The Mexican was shooting last summer, Roberts spent just 10 days on location in Real de Catorce in central Mexico. But that was enough to set the tone. When costar James Gandolfini arrived in the tiny town, "we all met to have a bite to eat," Roberts recalls, "and he grabbed me and threw me over his shoulder and gave me a whack on the butt." Far from being displeased, she says, "I thought, 'And we're off!' "

Were they ever. Roughing it in local digs where scorpions were regular visitors, Roberts had cast and crew members over in the evening for Italian and Mexican food cooked by a local chef. On weekends she drank margaritas at the crew's rowdy barbecues. "She would come out dancing with us," says producer Lawrence Bender. "She really enjoyed herself."

Another pastime Roberts enjoys is giving back. She recently donated $50,000 to the Arroyos Del Norte Elementary School near her 52-acre horse ranch in Taos, N.Mex., to build an athletic field—under the strict proviso that the school would not name it after her. And for the past three years she has spoken out on behalf of sufferers of a neurological disorder called Rett syndrome, which affects brain development in infancy. "The power of her celebrity and name is amazing," says New York City attorney <NODE id="8627" />David Brodsky<NODE id="8640" />, whose daughter <NODE id="8657" />Abigail<NODE id="8664" />, 10, appeared with Roberts in a documentary about the disorder after <NODE id="8734" />Julia<NODE id="8739" />'s sister <NODE id="8749" />Lisa<NODE id="8753" />, 35, introduced her to the Brodsky family. "She wants to do good things with it."

It doesn't take a Freud to analyze why, says her friend Garry Marshall. Roberts, who dotes on her niece, fledgling actress Emma Roberts, 10, "always goes to the children," he says. "All her charitable works come from the fact that she was not such a rich girl growing up."

What Roberts calls her "wonderfully dysfunctional" family was hardly destitute, but life wasn't always easy back in Smyrna, Ga. <NODE id="9239" />Roberts<NODE id="9246" />'s parents, <NODE id="9258" />Betty<NODE id="9263" />, now 66, a real estate agent, and <NODE id="9298" />Walter<NODE id="9304" />, a drama teacher, divorced when Julia was 4, splitting the family. (While <NODE id="9379" />Julia<NODE id="9384" /> and sister <NODE id="9396" />Lisa<NODE id="9400" />, now an actress, stayed with their mother, brother <NODE id="9452" />Eric<NODE id="9456" />, 44—an actor from whom both sisters are estranged—moved away with their father.) Six years later Walter died of cancer.

Despite her fractured home life, Roberts always "knew what she wanted," says Keith Gossett, her high school English teacher. "She had a special focus." Indeed, the lanky 18-year-old who left town for New York City in search of modeling and acting work has hardly looked back. She quickly landed on her feet, scoring a lead role in 1988's Mystic Pizza and following it up with the hugely successful Pretty Woman.

But the years that followed were anything but pretty: Roberts stumbled professionally, personally and publicly through ill-fated relationships (with Liam Neeson and Dylan McDermott, among others), her split from Sutherland just three days before their June 1991 wedding, and <NODE id="10266" />her<NODE id="10269" /> 21-month marriage to singer <NODE id="10298" />Lyle Lovett<NODE id="10309" />. "There was a time," says Gossett, "when I don't think she was at peace with herself."

Clearly that time has passed, thanks in no small part to Ben Bratt, whom she sometimes calls "my old man." The couple were introduced by friends in October 1997—when they found themselves dining in the same Manhattan restaurant—and have been inseparable since. "She is back to enjoying herself and having fun," says her childhood dentist Dr. Ted Aspes, "like the happy-go-lucky child I remember."

It certainly showed that night at Tavern on the Green, where Roberts happily signed autographs and posed for photos with a group of teenagers who were celebrating a birthday. Meanwhile, her own party was hotting up. " [Miramax Films boss] Harvey Weinstein showed up just to say hello," reports an observer. "Then out of nowhere Danny DeVito and Edward Norton came upstairs, and Harvey ordered two bottles of Dom Pérignon." He should have made it a case; Roberts could be celebrating for a while.

Anne-Marie O'Neill Natasha Stoynoff and Sue Miller in New York City, Frank Swertlow, Lorenzo Benet, Mark Dagostino and Robyn Flans in Los Angeles, Chris Coats in Houston, Jill Westfall in Atlanta and Linda Trischitta in Miami</TEXT>
<Meta /><Entities>
<Entity id="0" startPos="8627" endPos="8640" type="person" surface="David Brodsky">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="78_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="1" startPos="8657" endPos="8664" type="person" surface="Abigail">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="108_4" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="2" startPos="8734" endPos="8739" type="person" surface="Julia">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="185_3" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="3" startPos="8749" endPos="8753" type="person" surface="Lisa">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="200_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="4" startPos="9239" endPos="9246" type="person" surface="Roberts">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="0_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="5" startPos="9258" endPos="9263" type="person" surface="Betty">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="19_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="6" startPos="9298" endPos="9304" type="person" surface="Walter">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="59_3" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="7" startPos="9379" endPos="9384" type="person" surface="Julia">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="7_3" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="8" startPos="9396" endPos="9400" type="person" surface="Lisa">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="24_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="9" startPos="9452" endPos="9456" type="person" surface="Eric">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="80_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="10" startPos="10266" endPos="10269" type="person" surface="her">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="275_2" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity>
<Entity id="11" startPos="10298" endPos="10309" type="person" surface="Lyle Lovett">
<feature featureName="cm_id" featureValue="307_1" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." /></Entity></Entities><Relations>
<Relation id="12" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="1" label="person" />
<Entity id="0" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc81_8549_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="13" NAME="sibling_relationship">
<Entity id="2" label="person" />
<Entity id="3" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc81_8549_2" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="14" NAME="person_parent">
<Entity id="4" label="person" />
<Entity id="5" label="parent" />
<Entity id="6" label="parent" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc81_9239_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="15" NAME="marriage">
<Entity id="5" label="person" />
<Entity id="6" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc81_9239_2" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="16" NAME="sibling_relationship">
<Entity id="7" label="person" />
<Entity id="8" label="person" />
<Entity id="9" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="R.H., V.M." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc81_9372_1" />
</Relation>
<Relation id="17" NAME="marriage">
<Entity id="10" label="person" />
<Entity id="11" label="person" />
<feature featureName="annotator" featureValue="V.M., L.S." />
<feature featureName="rm_id" featureValue="doc81_9991_1_153" />
</Relation></Relations>
</Document>
